Hello, my name is Evelyn Riddell and with me is my co-presenter James Riddell.
안녕하세요, 제 이름은 Evelyn Riddell이고 저와 함께 공동 발표자인 James Riddell이 있습니다.
We are going to be giving a presentation on self-attention and transformers.
우리는 self-attention과 Transformers에 대해 프레젠테이션을 할 예정입니다.
This presentation was originally prepared for a computer science course at the University
이 프레젠테이션은 원래 대학의 컴퓨터 과학 과정을 위해 준비되었습니다.
of Waterloo, where we're both graduate students, and the course was given by Professor Wenhu
우리 둘 다 대학원생이고 Wenhu 교수가 강좌를 진행한 워털루의 대학입니다.
Chen.
첸.
All right, with that, let's get started.
좋습니다. 이제 시작하겠습니다.
So the goal for this presentation is to talk about what attention looked like before the
따라서 이 프레젠테이션의 목표는 관심이 이전에 어떤 모습이었는가에 대해 이야기하는 것입니다.
transformer architecture was introduced.
트랜스포머 아키텍처가 도입되었습니다.
In particular, this attention mechanism was highly coupled with an RNN structure, so we'll
특히 이 Attention 메커니즘은 RNN 구조와 밀접하게 결합되어 있으므로
go over that.
그 문제를 살펴보세요.
Then we'll shift to the attention is all you need paper that radically changed this field
그런 다음 우리는 이 분야를 근본적으로 변화시킨 논문이 필요한 전부라는 점에 주목하겠습니다.
of study, where they decoupled this from RNNs, introduced the transformer architecture,
RNN에서 이것을 분리하고 변환기 아키텍처를 도입한 연구에서
and had quite an impact with their paper.
그들의 논문에 상당한 영향을 미쳤습니다.
We'll also touch on transformers in other domains, in particular, the early adoption
또한 다른 영역의 변환기, 특히 조기 채택에 대해서도 다룰 것입니다.
of transformers in computer vision.
컴퓨터 비전의 변환기.
And the goal is to tackle some misconceptions along the way.
그리고 목표는 그 과정에서 몇 가지 오해를 해결하는 것입니다.
So the notion of exploiting context in machine learning and deep learning isn't new.
따라서 머신러닝과 딥러닝에서 컨텍스트를 활용한다는 개념은 새로운 것이 아닙니다.
So with CNNs, these exploit context from spatial locality, and this is particularly useful
따라서 CNN을 사용하면 공간적 지역성의 컨텍스트를 활용하며 이는 특히 유용합니다.
for images, where regions around a patch in an image give context for that particular
이미지의 경우 이미지의 패치 주변 영역이 해당 특정 항목에 대한 컨텍스트를 제공합니다.
patch.
반점.
With RNNs, context is exploited from temporal locality, and this is useful for sequences
RNN을 사용하면 시간적 지역성에서 컨텍스트가 활용되며 이는 시퀀스에 유용합니다.
or time series data.
또는 시계열 데이터.
But the way these work, the way that context is exploited is through the embedding of
그러나 이러한 작업 방식, 즉 컨텍스트를 활용하는 방식은 다음을 포함하는 것입니다.
priors into the model, and this forces them to pay attention to relevant features for
이는 모델에 대한 관련 기능에 주의를 기울이게 만듭니다.
a given problem.
주어진 문제.
And that given problem again is highly tied to the architecture and the way that these
그리고 주어진 문제는 아키텍처 및 이러한 방식과 밀접한 관련이 있습니다.
priors are embedded.
사전이 포함되어 있습니다.
What we now call self-attention in deep learning is, again, still this idea of paying attention
현재 딥러닝에서 셀프 어텐션(self-attention)이라고 부르는 것은 여전히 ​​주의를 기울이는 아이디어입니다.
to the most relevant parts or important parts of an input at a given time step, but without
주어진 시간 단계에서 입력의 가장 관련성이 높은 부분이나 중요한 부분에
these embedded priors, and ideally we'd like to learn what to pay attention to.
이러한 내장된 사전 변수가 있으며 이상적으로 우리는 무엇에 주의를 기울여야 하는지 배우고 싶습니다.
This is very useful for sequence-to-sequence modeling.
이는 시퀀스 간 모델링에 매우 유용합니다.
Now the attention mechanism typically refers to a function that allows a model to attend
이제 주의 메커니즘은 일반적으로 모델이 참석할 수 있도록 하는 기능을 나타냅니다.
to different context and content.
다양한 맥락과 내용으로.
And like I said before, ideally we'd like to learn this.
그리고 제가 전에 말했듯이 이상적으로 우리는 이것을 배우고 싶습니다.
So what we're learning here is the set attention functions or the parameters of this function.
그래서 우리가 여기서 배우는 것은 설정된 주의 함수 또는 이 함수의 매개변수입니다.
Now there's different ways that we can calculate attention.
이제 주의력을 계산할 수 있는 다양한 방법이 있습니다.
It can be additive or multiplicative, like with a dot product.
내적처럼 덧셈이나 곱셈이 가능합니다.
And we can also, we have different names to distinguish attention based on what is being
그리고 우리는 존재하는 것에 따라 주의를 구별하기 위해 다른 이름을 가질 수도 있습니다.
attended to.
참석.
So for self-attention, content is being attended to itself.
따라서 self-attention을 위해 콘텐츠는 그 자체에 집중됩니다.
We typically refer to this as intra-attention as well.
우리는 일반적으로 이것을 인트라어텐션(intra-attention)이라고도 합니다.
With cross-attention, content is attended to different content.
교차주의를 통해 콘텐츠는 다른 콘텐츠에 집중됩니다.
We often refer to this as encoder-decoder attention or intra-attention.
우리는 이것을 종종 인코더-디코더 어텐션 또는 인트라 어텐션이라고 부릅니다.
Now we'll talk about these, the ways to calculate attention and the different types of attention
이제 우리는 주의력을 계산하는 방법과 다양한 주의력 유형에 대해 이야기하겠습니다.
a little bit more later on, but this gives you a high-level overview of the different
나중에 좀 더 자세히 다루겠지만 이는 다양한 기능에 대한 높은 수준의 개요를 제공합니다.
terminologies used when talking about attention.
주의를 말할 때 사용하는 용어.
So like I said earlier, the attention function or attention mechanism is really useful for
앞서 말했듯이 주의 기능이나 주의 메커니즘은 다음과 같은 경우에 정말 유용합니다.
sequence-to-sequence modeling.
시퀀스 간 모델링.
So what this means is, when we're talking about sequence-to-sequence modeling, the goal
이것이 의미하는 바는 시퀀스 간 모델링에 관해 이야기할 때 목표는
is to take an input sequence, x, and produce a meaningful sequence, y, or an output sequence,
입력 시퀀스 x를 가져와 의미 있는 시퀀스 y 또는 출력 시퀀스를 생성하는 것입니다.
y.
그리고.
Now this could look like text-to-text, where the input sequence is text and the output
이제 이는 입력 순서가 텍스트이고 출력이 텍스트인 텍스트 대 텍스트처럼 보일 수 있습니다.
sequence is text.
순서는 텍스트입니다.
Think of tasks like question answering, translation, or text summarization.
질문 답변, 번역, 텍스트 요약과 같은 작업을 생각해 보세요.
Now this input sequence doesn't have to be text, it could also be an image.
이제 이 입력 시퀀스는 텍스트일 필요는 없으며 이미지일 수도 있습니다.
Think of image captioning, where we take an image and produce a caption, which embodies
이미지를 촬영하고 캡션을 생성하는 이미지 캡션을 생각해 보세요.
the output sequence.
출력 순서.
Now we don't just go from the input sequence to the output sequence with some sort of magical
이제 우리는 일종의 마법 같은 방식으로 입력 시퀀스에서 출력 시퀀스로 이동하는 것이 아닙니다.
black box, often we use encoder decoder models.
블랙박스에서는 인코더 디코더 모델을 자주 사용합니다.
The way that this works is the input sequence is encoded by an encoder, which then shares
이것이 작동하는 방식은 입력 시퀀스가 ​​인코더에 의해 인코딩되어 공유되는 것입니다.
a state and a context vector, which captures the information and all the context from the
상태 및 컨텍스트 벡터는 정보와 모든 컨텍스트를 캡처합니다.
input sequence, shares that with the decoder, which then meaningfully decodes this information
입력 시퀀스는 이를 디코더와 공유하여 이 정보를 의미 있게 디코딩합니다.
to produce an output sequence.
출력 시퀀스를 생성합니다.
And it all depends on what the task is, of course, and what these sequences are.
그리고 그것은 물론 작업이 무엇인지, 그리고 이러한 순서가 무엇인지에 따라 달라집니다.
And usually these encoder decoder models are implemented using RNNs, these are highly useful
그리고 일반적으로 이러한 인코더 디코더 모델은 RNN을 사용하여 구현되며 매우 유용합니다.
for sequences sequence modeling.
시퀀스 시퀀스 모델링을 위한 것입니다.
And also the transformer architecture is a type of encoder decoder model useful for these
또한 변환기 아키텍처는 이러한 용도에 유용한 일종의 인코더 디코더 모델입니다.
types of tasks.
작업 유형.
And of course we'll cover that later.
물론 이에 대해서는 나중에 다루겠습니다.
But first we're going to start talking, we'll start first with an explanation of how RNNs
하지만 먼저 이야기를 시작하겠습니다. 먼저 RNN이 어떻게 작동하는지에 대한 설명부터 시작하겠습니다.
can be used for sequence to sequence modeling.
시퀀스 간 모델링에 사용할 수 있습니다.
Here we have a paper from 2014 called Sequence to Sequence Learning with Neural Networks
여기에 신경망을 이용한 Sequence to Sequence Learning이라는 2014년 논문이 있습니다.
that does sequence to sequence modeling with RNNs using this encoder decoder structure.
이 인코더 디코더 구조를 사용하여 RNN으로 시퀀스 대 시퀀스 모델링을 수행합니다.
The encoder and the decoder are both instantiated using an LSDM, which is a type of recurrent
인코더와 디코더는 모두 순환 알고리즘의 일종인 LSDM을 사용하여 인스턴스화됩니다.
neural network.
신경망.
And the way this works is the encoder starts with the input sequence.
이것이 작동하는 방식은 인코더가 입력 시퀀스로 시작하는 것입니다.
Let's say for now this input sequence has four tokens, X1, X2, X3, and X4.
지금은 이 입력 시퀀스에 X1, X2, X3, X4라는 4개의 토큰이 있다고 가정해 보겠습니다.
Using these input tokens, we calculate the hidden states of the encoder.
이러한 입력 토큰을 사용하여 인코더의 숨겨진 상태를 계산합니다.
Now for each token, we calculate its corresponding hidden states.
이제 각 토큰에 대해 해당 숨겨진 상태를 계산합니다.
So let's say for token X2, we calculate hidden state 2.
토큰 X2에 대해 숨겨진 상태 2를 계산한다고 가정해 보겠습니다.
But it also requires the previous hidden state to inform that hidden state.
하지만 해당 숨겨진 상태를 알리려면 이전 숨겨진 상태도 필요합니다.
So for H2, we use H1 to help inform what that hidden state looks like.
따라서 H2의 경우 H1을 사용하여 숨겨진 상태가 어떻게 생겼는지 알려줍니다.
And we do this for all of the hidden states and all of the tokens until we get to the
그리고 우리는 다음 단계에 도달할 때까지 모든 숨겨진 상태와 모든 토큰에 대해 이 작업을 수행합니다.
end of the sequence.
시퀀스의 끝.
But notice here, when we're calculating H4, we require the previous hidden state and
하지만 여기서 주목하세요. H4를 계산할 때 이전 숨겨진 상태가 필요하며
the one before that and the one before that.
그 전의 것과 그 전의 것.
So we end up with these dependencies where whatever the previous tokens and those hidden
따라서 우리는 이전 토큰과 숨겨진 토큰이 무엇이든 이러한 종속성을 갖게 됩니다.
states were inform what the next hidden states are.
상태는 다음 숨겨진 상태가 무엇인지 알려줍니다.
But as the sequences get longer, this information gets watered down.
그러나 시퀀스가 ​​길어질수록 이 정보는 약해집니다.
And again, remember RNNs use spatial locality as an embedded prior, right, where the hidden
그리고 다시 말하지만, RNN은 공간적 지역성을 내장된 사전 정보로 사용한다는 점을 기억하세요.
states or the tokens closest to a hidden state or token have the most impact, have
숨겨진 상태 또는 토큰에 가장 가까운 상태 또는 토큰이 가장 큰 영향을 미칩니다.
the biggest effect.
가장 큰 효과.
But long range dependencies, so inputs or tokens that happened earlier in the sequence,
그러나 장거리 종속성으로 인해 시퀀스 초기에 발생한 입력이나 토큰은
don't have as much impact anymore.
더 이상 큰 영향을 미치지 않습니다.
Now the way that this progresses now is once this token has been encoded, or these tokens,
이제 이것이 진행되는 방식은 이 토큰이 인코딩된 후입니다.
this input sequence has been encoded, the last hidden state is used to calculate a context
이 입력 시퀀스는 인코딩되었으며 마지막 숨겨진 상태는 컨텍스트를 계산하는 데 사용됩니다.
vector and an initial state for the decoder.
벡터와 디코더의 초기 상태.
The context vector captures the information from the input sequence.
컨텍스트 벡터는 입력 시퀀스의 정보를 캡처합니다.
From there, we do a very similar process where we use previous hidden state and the previous
거기에서 우리는 이전 숨겨진 상태와 이전 숨겨진 상태를 사용하는 매우 유사한 프로세스를 수행합니다.
output token to calculate the next output token.
출력 토큰을 사용하여 다음 출력 토큰을 계산합니다.
So we do this in a recurrent autoregressive fashion, recurrent in this case, because again,
따라서 우리는 반복적인 자기회귀 방식으로 이 작업을 수행합니다. 이 경우에는 반복됩니다. 왜냐하면 다시 말하지만,
we use the previous hidden state to calculate the next one.
이전 숨겨진 상태를 사용하여 다음 상태를 계산합니다.
We do this for each output token that we're generating until we've arrived at an output
출력에 도달할 때까지 생성하는 각 출력 토큰에 대해 이 작업을 수행합니다.
sequence.
순서.
Now again, a hidden state is informed by, of course, its previous output token, but also
이제 다시 숨겨진 상태에 대한 정보는 물론 이전 출력 토큰을 통해 알 수 있을 뿐만 아니라
all the hidden states that come before it.
그 앞에 오는 모든 숨겨진 상태.
Again, it's this notion of leveraging spatial locality, which is that embedded prior that
다시 말하지만, 이는 공간적 지역성을 활용하는 개념입니다.
the RNN exploits.
RNN 악용.
But we see that again, whatever happened earlier in the sequence for the output gets watered
그러나 우리는 출력 시퀀스에서 이전에 발생한 일이 무엇이든 물에 젖어 있다는 것을 다시 알 수 있습니다.
down as we get further and further in this sequence.
이 순서대로 점점 더 나아가면 아래로 내려갑니다.
Now another issue that we see is this context vector is reused for every hidden state of
이제 우리가 볼 수 있는 또 다른 문제는 이 컨텍스트 벡터가 모든 숨겨진 상태에 재사용된다는 것입니다.
the decoder.
디코더.
We just use a single context vector that's supposed to capture all of the information
우리는 모든 정보를 캡처하는 단일 컨텍스트 벡터를 사용합니다.
from the inputs.
입력에서.
But this tends to result in an informational bottleneck because of this fixed length context
그러나 이는 고정 길이 컨텍스트로 인해 정보 병목 현상이 발생하는 경향이 있습니다.
vector.
벡터.
The problem here is that if our inputs get really long, this context vector might not
여기서 문제는 입력이 너무 길어지면 이 컨텍스트 벡터가 그렇지 않을 수도 있다는 것입니다.
be able to capture all the information, but more importantly, as we're generating new
모든 정보를 캡처할 수 있지만 더 중요한 것은 새로운 정보를 생성하고 있다는 것입니다.
output tokens, certain parts of the input might be more relevant or might be more important,
출력 토큰, 입력의 특정 부분이 더 관련성이 높거나 더 중요할 수 있습니다.
and this context vector, the single context vector might not capture that.
그리고 이 컨텍스트 벡터는 단일 컨텍스트 벡터가 이를 캡처하지 못할 수도 있습니다.
So another paper from 2015 called Neural Machine Translation by Jointly Learning to Align
2015년의 또 다른 논문인 Neural Machine Translation by Jointly Learning to Align
and Translate addressed this informational bottleneck.
그리고 Translate는 이러한 정보 병목 현상을 해결했습니다.
They introduced the idea of using a different context vector for each time step in the decoder.
그들은 디코더의 각 시간 단계에 대해 서로 다른 컨텍스트 벡터를 사용하는 아이디어를 도입했습니다.
So the process is very similar, but instead of using that single context vector that's
따라서 프로세스는 매우 유사하지만 단일 컨텍스트 벡터를 사용하는 대신
used for each decoder hidden state, we're going to calculate a new one for each decoder
각 디코더의 숨겨진 상태에 사용되므로 각 디코더에 대해 새로운 상태를 계산하겠습니다.
hidden state, and we can craft it so that it looks at or captures the most important
숨겨진 상태를 보고 가장 중요한 것을 보거나 포착하도록 만들 수 있습니다.
parts of the input sequence for that time step.
해당 시간 단계에 대한 입력 시퀀스의 일부입니다.
So the way we do this is we saw the same setup where we encode, produce an initial state
그래서 우리가 하는 방식은 인코딩하고 초기 상태를 생성하는 것과 동일한 설정을 보는 것입니다.
for the decoder, but instead of just calculating a single context vector that's going to be
디코더의 경우 단일 컨텍스트 벡터를 계산하는 대신
used at every step of the decoder, we're calculating a new one.
디코더의 모든 단계에서 사용되어 새로운 것을 계산하고 있습니다.
So how this works is we calculate first the alignment between each hidden state of the
이것이 작동하는 방식은 먼저 각 숨겨진 상태 사이의 정렬을 계산하는 것입니다.
encoder with the previous decoder state.
이전 디코더 상태를 갖는 인코더.
So in this case, for S1, to calculate context vector 1, we need that previous hidden state,
따라서 이 경우 S1에 대해 컨텍스트 벡터 1을 계산하려면 이전 숨겨진 상태가 필요합니다.
in this case S0.
이 경우 S0.
So we calculate the alignment scores using an attention function.
그래서 우리는 attention 함수를 사용하여 정렬 점수를 계산합니다.
Now for now, let's keep this abstract.
지금은 이 추상적인 내용을 유지해 보겠습니다.
We'll get to what this looks like later, but it calculates the alignment or the compatibility
이것이 어떻게 보이는지는 나중에 살펴보겠지만 정렬이나 호환성을 계산합니다.
between the hidden states and that decoder state.
숨겨진 상태와 해당 디코더 상태 사이.
We then normalize these alignment scores to produce the attention weights, and then
그런 다음 이러한 정렬 점수를 정규화하여 주의 가중치를 생성한 다음
we calculate a weighted sum.
가중 합계를 계산합니다.
So what's going on here is we use the attention weights to say how much of each hidden state
여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지는 주의 가중치를 사용하여 각 숨겨진 상태가 얼마나 되는지 확인하는 것입니다.
are we going to use to inform what this context vector is.
이 컨텍스트 벡터가 무엇인지 알려주는 데 사용할 것입니다.
So that way we're saying, okay, hidden states with high attention weights.
그래서 우리는 주의 가중치가 높은 숨겨진 상태를 말하는 것입니다.
Our weighted higher city will have more impact when we go to calculate this next hidden state
가중치가 높은 도시는 다음 숨겨진 상태를 계산할 때 더 많은 영향을 미칠 것입니다.
and therefore that next output token.
따라서 다음 출력 토큰입니다.
So essentially what these attention weights mean is or represent is they represent the
따라서 본질적으로 이러한 주의 가중치가 의미하거나 나타내는 것은
measure that the target word, in this case Y1, is aligned to or translated from a source
대상 단어(이 경우 Y1)가 소스에 정렬되거나 소스에서 번역되었는지 측정합니다.
word XI, which is corresponded with each hidden state HI.
각 은닉 상태 HI에 대응되는 워드 XI.
It also reflects the importance of the annotation, therefore, the hidden states with respect
또한 주석의 중요성을 반영하므로 관련 숨겨진 상태가 표시됩니다.
to the previous hidden state, because we're using the previous hidden state and all of
이전 숨겨진 상태로 전환합니다. 왜냐하면 우리는 이전 숨겨진 상태와 모든 항목을 사용하고 있기 때문입니다.
the different annotation vectors or hidden states of the encoder to calculate that context
해당 컨텍스트를 계산하기 위한 인코더의 다양한 주석 벡터 또는 숨겨진 상태
vector and generate the next output token.
벡터를 생성하고 다음 출력 토큰을 생성합니다.
So we do this for each step or each hidden state of the decoder.
그래서 우리는 디코더의 각 단계나 숨겨진 상태에 대해 이 작업을 수행합니다.
We calculate a new context vector using the previous hidden state of the decoder and the
디코더의 이전 숨겨진 상태를 사용하여 새로운 컨텍스트 벡터를 계산합니다.
previous output token generated by the decoder to inform what the next hidden state and the
다음 숨겨진 상태와 상태를 알리기 위해 디코더에 의해 생성된 이전 출력 토큰
next output token are going to be.
다음 출력 토큰이 될 것입니다.
So this is our recurrent autoregressive process in which we do this.
이것이 우리가 하는 반복적인 자기회귀 과정입니다.
So what we've done is we've solved the issue now of capturing the most important parts
그래서 우리가 한 일은 이제 가장 중요한 부분을 포착하는 문제를 해결한 것입니다.
of the input for generating each token in the output.
출력에서 각 토큰을 생성하기 위한 입력입니다.
Now one thing we haven't really solved though is the fact that the recurrent structure
이제 우리가 실제로 해결하지 못한 한 가지는 순환 구조가
of this, as our decoder produces more and more output tokens and each previous decoder
우리의 디코더가 점점 더 많은 출력 토큰과 이전의 각 디코더를 생성함에 따라
state informs what the next decoder state is going to be, we still lose some information
상태는 다음 디코더 상태가 무엇인지 알려주지만 여전히 일부 정보를 잃습니다.
about what previous hidden states or output tokens were generated.
이전에 어떤 숨겨진 상태나 출력 토큰이 생성되었는지에 대해 설명합니다.
Now our encoder is bidirectional in this case, which allows for the annotation of each word
이제 이 경우 인코더는 양방향이므로 각 단어에 주석을 달 수 있습니다.
to summarize both preceding and following words.
앞의 단어와 뒤의 단어를 모두 요약합니다.
So we get this back and forth information.
그래서 우리는 이 정보를 앞뒤로 얻습니다.
We capture the most important parts of the input, so that part is solved with this attention
입력의 가장 중요한 부분을 포착하여 그 부분을 이런 관심으로 해결합니다.
mechanism.
기구.
Now all steps are differentiable, so we can back propagate through everything and update
이제 모든 단계가 미분 가능하므로 모든 단계를 역전파하고 업데이트할 수 있습니다.
the model parameters.
모델 매개변수.
So to provide a visualization for these attention weights, the authors of this paper produce
따라서 이러한 주의 가중치에 대한 시각화를 제공하기 위해 이 논문의 저자는
this visualization for the task of translation.
번역 작업을 위한 시각화입니다.
In this case we have an English sentence on top and a French sentence on the left hand
이 경우 상단에는 영어 문장이 있고 왼쪽에는 프랑스어 문장이 있습니다.
side.
옆.
Here the pixels are colored or pixelated with a brightness that corresponds to the attention
여기서 픽셀은 주의에 해당하는 밝기로 색상이 지정되거나 픽셀화됩니다.
weight.
무게.
So the more bright, the higher the attention weight.
따라서 밝을수록 주의 가중치가 높아집니다.
What this means is that the model was paying attention to particular inputs when generating
이것이 의미하는 바는 모델이 생성할 때 특정 입력에 주의를 기울였다는 것입니다.
an output token.
출력 토큰.
So let's look at the word agreement.
그럼 합의라는 단어를 살펴보겠습니다.
When the model was producing the word agreement in French, it was paying attention to the
모델이 프랑스어로 합의라는 단어를 생산할 때,
word agreement in the English sentence, so that's why we see a highly pixelated or bright
영어 문장의 단어 일치는 픽셀화되거나 밝은 부분을 보는 이유입니다.
pixel here in this visualization.
이 시각화의 픽셀은 여기입니다.
So when we see a nice diagonal of bright pixels, it represents that there was a nice
따라서 밝은 픽셀의 멋진 대각선을 보면 좋은 픽셀이 있다는 것을 나타냅니다.
one-to-one correspondence of English to French words.
영어와 프랑스어 단어의 일대일 대응.
Now we don't see that everywhere, of course.
물론 이제 우리는 그것을 모든 곳에서 볼 수는 없습니다.
This is usually due to either a different ordering of words that occur in different languages.
이는 일반적으로 다른 언어에서 발생하는 단어의 순서가 다르기 때문입니다.
So for example, European economic area, we see the diagonal in the other direction because
예를 들어 유럽 경제 지역에서는 대각선이 반대 방향으로 보입니다.
the French ordering of words is different, sort of inverted, or we see some ambiguity
프랑스어 단어 순서가 다르거나, 일종의 반전이 있거나, 모호함을 볼 수 있습니다.
that arises because of different semantic meanings of different words.
이는 서로 다른 단어의 의미론적 의미가 다르기 때문에 발생합니다.
For example, the word was in English and aité in French, again, can represent different
예를 들어 영어로 was라는 단어와 프랑스어로 aité라는 단어는 서로 다른 의미를 나타낼 수 있습니다.
things, which means that the model was paying attention to other words as well when generating
이는 모델이 생성할 때 다른 단어에도 주의를 기울였다는 것을 의미합니다.
the words in French that represent the translated representation of those words in the English
영어로 된 해당 단어의 번역된 표현을 나타내는 프랑스어 단어
sentence.
문장.
But it gives a nice idea for what the attention weights looks like, what the model was paying
하지만 이는 주의 가중치가 어떻게 생겼는지, 모델이 지불한 금액에 대한 좋은 아이디어를 제공합니다.
attention to when generating the outputs for this particular task.
이 특정 작업에 대한 출력을 생성할 때 주의하세요.
The authors compared their approach with the RNN and attention process with just a regular
저자는 자신의 접근 방식을 RNN과 일반 관심 프로세스와 비교했습니다.
RNN encoder-decoder structure, and they used two training paradigms, one with 30-word sentences
RNN 인코더-디코더 구조, 두 개의 훈련 패러다임(하나는 30단어 문장 포함)을 사용했습니다.
and another with 50-word sentences.
또 다른 하나는 50단어 문장입니다.
And what we see here is that the RNN with the attention mechanism built in on the 50-word
여기서 볼 수 있는 것은 주의 메커니즘이 50개 단어에 내장된 RNN이라는 것입니다.
training paradigm, we observe no performance segregation for longer sentence lengths.
훈련 패러다임에서는 더 긴 문장 길이에 대한 성능 분리가 관찰되지 않습니다.
Now this is because we made sure that the decoder knew what was important to pay attention
이제 이는 디코더가 주의를 기울여야 할 중요한 것이 무엇인지 알고 있는지 확인했기 때문입니다.
to from the input, so we have a specialized context vector for each decoder time step
입력으로부터 각 디코더 시간 단계에 대해 특화된 컨텍스트 벡터를 갖게 됩니다.
when generating each new output token.
각각의 새로운 출력 토큰을 생성할 때.
Now keep in mind that we're only looking at 50-60 sentence lengths, so we would probably
이제 우리는 50~60개의 문장 길이만 보고 있으므로 아마도
still see some degradation as sentence lengths increase even more because we get that watered
물을 주었기 때문에 문장 길이가 훨씬 더 늘어나면서 여전히 약간의 저하가 보입니다.
down effect in the decoder sequence.
디코더 시퀀스의 다운 효과.
Now a different paper from also 2015 called Show, Attend, and Tell, Neural Image Caption
이제 Show, Attend, and Tell, Neural Image Caption이라는 2015년의 다른 논문이 있습니다.
Generation with Visual Attention, they use this RNN with attention, but for a different
시각적 주의를 갖춘 생성에서는 주의를 기울여 이 RNN을 사용하지만 다른 용도로 사용됩니다.
task, they don't use a text input sequence, they use an image sequence for image captioning.
작업에서는 텍스트 입력 시퀀스를 사용하지 않고 이미지 캡션을 위해 이미지 시퀀스를 사용합니다.
It builds directly on this previous paper, and the way they do this is they have a very
그것은 이 이전 논문을 바탕으로 직접 구축되었으며, 그들이 이를 수행하는 방식은 매우
similar setup, but instead of using the text as the input sequence, they take their image
유사한 설정이지만 텍스트를 입력 시퀀스로 사용하는 대신 이미지를 사용합니다.
and extract the features using a convolutional neural network to produce the hidden states
숨겨진 상태를 생성하기 위해 컨볼루셔널 신경망을 사용하여 특징을 추출합니다.
of the encoder.
인코더의.
Essentially these are feature vectors of the image that represent different image regions.
기본적으로 이는 다양한 이미지 영역을 나타내는 이미지의 특징 벡터입니다.
So when we then go to generate the output sequence using the decoder, a new context vector is
따라서 디코더를 사용하여 출력 시퀀스를 생성할 때 새로운 컨텍스트 벡터는 다음과 같습니다.
calculated for each decoder hidden state, and it tends to different image regions, which
각 디코더의 숨겨진 상태에 대해 계산되며 서로 다른 이미지 영역이 되는 경향이 있습니다.
are captured by the feature vectors or the hidden states of the encoder.
특징 벡터 또는 인코더의 숨겨진 상태로 캡처됩니다.
We still calculate the alignment scores, the attention weights, and then do that weighted
우리는 여전히 정렬 점수, 주의 가중치를 계산하고 가중치를 적용하여 계산합니다.
sum that informs what the context vector is, and the idea here is that the attention weights
컨텍스트 벡터가 무엇인지 알려주는 합계이며 여기서 아이디어는 주의 가중치라는 것입니다.
indicate how much of the different regions of the image are important when generating
이미지를 생성할 때 이미지의 다양한 영역이 얼마나 중요한지 나타냅니다.
that output token.
그 출력 토큰.
Now we do this still in an autoregressive recurrent fashion, recurrent because we're using the
이제 우리는 자동 회귀 방식으로 이 작업을 수행합니다.
previous decoder states to inform what the next decoder states are going to be, and the
이전 디코더 상태는 다음 디코더 상태가 무엇인지 알려줍니다.
next output tokens are going to be, but we're calculating a new context vector for each
다음 출력 토큰이 될 예정이지만 각각에 대해 새로운 컨텍스트 벡터를 계산하고 있습니다.
time step.
시간 단계.
All steps are differentiable, so we can back propagate through everything and update model
모든 단계는 미분 가능하므로 모든 단계를 역전파하고 모델을 업데이트할 수 있습니다.
parameters, and each context vector in this case attends to different image regions.
매개변수, 그리고 이 경우 각 컨텍스트 벡터는 서로 다른 이미지 영역에 사용됩니다.
Telling the model here for this token, for this hidden state, we're paying attention to
이 토큰과 숨겨진 상태에 대해 여기 모델에 알려주는 것은 다음과 같습니다.
this region or that region to inform what that token should be for the output.
출력을 위해 해당 토큰이 무엇인지 알려주기 위해 이 지역 또는 해당 지역을 사용합니다.
Now to give you a visualization, here it gives insight to where and what the attention focused
이제 시각화를 제공하기 위해 여기서는 관심이 집중된 위치와 대상에 대한 통찰력을 제공합니다.
on when generating each word. So here we still have this image of the bird.
각 단어를 생성할 때 켜집니다. 그래서 여기에 우리는 여전히 새의 이미지를 가지고 있습니다.
Let's look at when the model produced the word bird. At that time step, the model was
모델이 언제 Bird라는 단어를 생성했는지 살펴보겠습니다. 그 당시 모델은 다음과 같습니다.
paying attention to the region where the bird was. So that's how the model knew to produce
새가 있던 지역에주의를 기울이십시오. 그래서 모델이 생산하는 방법을 알았습니다.
the word bird for that region of the image. Now if we go down and look further through
이미지의 해당 영역에 대한 새라는 단어입니다. 이제 아래로 내려가 좀 더 자세히 살펴보면
the sequence where water was produced, at that point the model was paying attention to
물이 생성되는 순서, 그 시점에서 모델이 주의를 기울인 부분
the area around the bird where the water was, and so it makes sense that the word water was
물이 있었던 새 주변 지역이므로 물이라는 단어가
then produced by the model. Now the paper, they introduced two ways of calculating attention.
그런 다음 모델에 의해 생산됩니다. 이제 논문에서는 주의력을 계산하는 두 가지 방법을 소개했습니다.
There's a deterministic soft attention, which is what I've explained to you so far. There's another
결정론적인 소프트 어텐션(soft attention)이 있는데, 이것이 바로 제가 지금까지 설명드린 것입니다. 또 있어요
way to do it, which they refer to as stochastic hard attention, which requires reinforcement
이를 수행하는 방법은 강화가 필요한 확률론적 하드 주의(stochastic hard attention)라고 합니다.
learning. This is something you're interested in. I highly recommend you read the paper.
학습. 이것은 여러분이 관심을 갖고 있는 내용입니다. 해당 논문을 읽어 보시기를 적극 권장합니다.
It's beyond the scope for this presentation. Now here's a couple more visualizations
이는 이 프레젠테이션의 범위를 벗어납니다. 이제 몇 가지 시각화가 더 있습니다.
to really just reinforce this idea. Let's look at the first picture where a woman is throwing
이 아이디어를 실제로 강화하는 것입니다. 여자가 던지는 첫 번째 사진을 보자
a frisbee. At the time where the model was paying attention to this region where the frisbee was,
프리스비. 모델이 프리스비가 있던 이 부위에 주목하던 당시,
it produced the word frisbee in the caption.
캡션에 frisbee라는 단어가 생성되었습니다.
Okay, so we've talked now about how attention was incorporated into the encoder-decoder structure
좋아요, 이제 우리는 주의가 인코더-디코더 구조에 어떻게 통합되었는지에 대해 이야기했습니다.
with RNNs. Now in 2017, Vaswani and his colleagues published the Attention is All You Need paper,
RNN으로. 2017년에 Vaswani와 그의 동료들은 Attention is All You Need 논문을 발표했습니다.
and this was a pretty radical paper at the time, and it still is. It's been very impactful and
이 논문은 그 당시에는 상당히 급진적인 논문이었으며 지금도 그렇습니다. 매우 임팩트가 있었고
fundamental for a lot of AI technologies that we now know and use today. They decoupled attention
오늘날 우리가 알고 사용하는 많은 AI 기술의 기본입니다. 그들은 주의를 분리시켰습니다
from the RNN structure and introduced the transformer architecture.
RNN 구조에서 변환기 아키텍처를 도입했습니다.
So let's dive right into that, but before we do it, I want to take a brief moment to talk to you
그럼 바로 본론으로 들어가겠습니다. 하지만 그 전에 잠시 여러분과 이야기를 나누고 싶습니다.
about feature superposition and polycemiticity. So remember working with deep neural networks,
특징 중첩과 다형성에 대해. 심층 신경망으로 작업한 것을 기억하세요.
neural activations often do not represent a single thing, and this happens because neural networks
신경 활성화는 단일한 것을 나타내지 않는 경우가 많으며, 이는 신경 네트워크 때문에 발생합니다.
want to represent more features than they have neurons for. And we see this with deep neural
뉴런이 가지고 있는 것보다 더 많은 특징을 표현하고 싶어합니다. 그리고 우리는 이것을 심층 신경으로 봅니다.
networks like the transformer architecture. With this, we observe that often many unrelated
트랜스포머 아키텍처와 같은 네트워크. 이를 통해 우리는 종종 관련되지 않은 많은
concepts are packed into single neurons. This results in the superposition of features.
개념은 단일 뉴런으로 압축됩니다. 이로 인해 특성이 중첩됩니다.
This is important because when we're talking about tokens and inputs and outputs to
이는 토큰과 입력 및 출력에 대해 이야기할 때 중요합니다.
deep learning network layers or parts of those layers, it doesn't make sense to think of these
딥 러닝 네트워크 계층 또는 해당 계층의 일부를 생각하는 것은 의미가 없습니다.
inputs and outputs as tokens or words like we've been doing before. These tend to lose meaning
이전에 해왔던 것처럼 토큰이나 단어로 입력과 출력을 수행합니다. 이는 의미를 잃는 경향이 있습니다.
as we get deeper and deeper into the network. Instead, we're going to be thinking of them as
우리는 네트워크에 점점 더 깊이 들어가게 됩니다. 대신, 우리는 그들을 다음과 같이 생각할 것입니다.
abstract or generic vectors, let's say. And again, this is due to this polycemiticity that
추상적이거나 일반적인 벡터라고 가정해 보겠습니다. 그리고 다시 말하지만, 이것은 다원성 때문입니다.
arises with deep neural networks. Now, the unfortunate side effect of this is the decreased
심층 신경망에서 발생합니다. 이제 이것의 불행한 부작용은 감소입니다.
explainability in deep neural networks. There is some research being done in this area to
심층 신경망의 설명 가능성. 이 분야에서 몇 가지 연구가 진행되고 있습니다.
add explainability back into deep neural networks like LLMs, which is being done by Anthropic.
Anthropic에서 수행 중인 LLM과 같은 심층 신경망에 설명 기능을 다시 추가합니다.
But for now, it's still quite an unsolved problem, and we just need to be careful when working with
하지만 현재로서는 여전히 해결되지 않은 문제이므로 작업할 때 주의하면 됩니다.
deep neural networks or talking or thinking about them that we don't associate inputs and outputs
입력과 출력을 연관시키지 않는 심층 신경망 또는 이에 대해 이야기하거나 생각하는 것
with tangible things like words or tokens because that's not what happens. It's because of the
단어나 토큰과 같은 유형의 것에는 그런 일이 일어나지 않기 때문입니다. 때문이에요
superposition and polycemiticity that occurs. Okay, with that in mind, let's move on.
중첩과 다중성이 발생한다. 좋아요, 그 점을 염두에 두고 다음으로 넘어가겠습니다.
I'm going to give a quick overview of the attention that we've seen so far.
지금까지 우리가 보았던 관심에 대해 간략하게 개요를 말씀드리겠습니다.
What we've seen so far is what we now refer to as additive recurrent attention. So additive
지금까지 우리가 본 것은 이제 부가적 반복 주의(additive recurrent attention)라고 부르는 것입니다. 그래서 첨가물
because of the choice for the attention function, which in both cases that I've talked about before,
주의 기능을 선택했기 때문입니다. 두 경우 모두 이전에 말씀드렸듯이
is a simple feedforward network. It's an MLP network, and it's an additive calculation.
간단한 피드포워드 네트워크입니다. 이것은 MLP 네트워크이고 덧셈 계산입니다.
The recurrent part of this attention mechanism is the fact that we need the previous decoder
이 주의 메커니즘의 반복되는 부분은 이전 디코더가 필요하다는 사실입니다.
hidden state to calculate the next one. In this case, this image, the ST-1 is the previous
다음 상태를 계산하는 숨겨진 상태. 이 경우, 이 이미지는 ST-1이 이전의
decoder hidden state. We calculate the alignment of this hidden state with all of the encoder hidden
디코더 숨겨진 상태. 모든 인코더가 숨겨진 상태에서 이 숨겨진 상태의 정렬을 계산합니다.
state that H is to then inform what the context vector is to then produce the next decoder hidden
H는 컨텍스트 벡터가 무엇인지 알려주고 숨겨진 다음 디코더를 생성한다고 명시합니다.
state. So this is this recurrent notion of need the previous to produce the next.
상태. 그래서 이것은 다음을 생산하기 위해 이전이 필요하다는 반복되는 개념입니다.
Now, there's some issues with this recurrent structure. The first is the scalability issue
이제 이 반복 구조에는 몇 가지 문제가 있습니다. 첫 번째는 확장성 문제입니다.
with this. Performance degrades as a distance between words increases. Now, we talked already about
이것으로. 단어 사이의 거리가 멀어질수록 성능이 저하됩니다. 자, 우리는 이미 그것에 대해 이야기했습니다.
that context vector bottleneck that the attention mechanism addresses. We address this
주의 메커니즘이 해결하는 컨텍스트 벡터 병목 현상입니다. 우리는 이 문제를 해결합니다
dilution of information from the encoder that captures the information from the inputs to
입력에서 정보를 캡처하는 인코더의 정보 희석
the decoder. But still, as we produce longer outputs, output sequences in the decoder,
디코더. 그러나 여전히 더 긴 출력을 생성함에 따라 디코더의 출력 시퀀스는
information from earlier decoder hidden states and output tokens, these get watered down and
이전 디코더 숨겨진 상태 및 출력 토큰의 정보는 희석되어
diluted. We see these long range dependencies, and that's just why recurrent neural networks
희석. 우리는 이러한 장거리 의존성을 보고 있으며 이것이 바로 순환 신경망이 존재하는 이유입니다.
don't scale very well. We also have parallelization limitations. Recurrent processes lack the ability
잘 확장되지 않습니다. 병렬화에도 한계가 있습니다. 반복되는 프로세스에는 능력이 부족합니다.
to be parallelized. There's really only so much we can parallelize because we need previous hidden
병렬화됩니다. 이전 숨겨진 항목이 필요하기 때문에 병렬화할 수 있는 것이 실제로 너무 많습니다.
states and previous output tokens to inform what the next hidden states and next output tokens are
다음 숨겨진 상태와 다음 출력 토큰이 무엇인지 알려주는 상태 및 이전 출력 토큰
going to be. And then we have memory constraints. RNNs are notoriously known for having limited
될 것. 그리고 메모리 제약이 있습니다. RNN은 제한적인 것으로 악명이 높습니다.
memories, memory and struggle with those long range dependencies. There's that diluted impact of
기억, 기억, 장거리 의존성에 대한 투쟁. 희석된 영향이 있습니다.
earlier elements on output sequences as the sequence progresses. So how can we address these
시퀀스가 진행됨에 따라 출력 시퀀스의 이전 요소. 그렇다면 이러한 문제를 어떻게 해결할 수 있을까요?
issues? Well, one way to do it is to decouple the attention from the RNN structure. We want to
문제? 이를 수행하는 한 가지 방법은 RNN 구조에서 주의를 분리하는 것입니다. 우리는 원한다
separate, the goal is to separate the attention mechanism into smaller self-contained components
분리, 목표는 어텐션 메커니즘을 더 작은 자체 포함 구성 요소로 분리하는 것입니다.
that we can hopefully parallelize. Now remember that the attention is purely the
우리는 희망적으로 병렬화할 수 있습니다. 이제 관심은 순전히
act of determining the importance of elements to be passed forward in the model. We do this by
모델에서 전달될 요소의 중요성을 결정하는 행위. 우리는 이것을 통해
calculating the attention weights, which lets the model pay attention to the most significant parts.
모델이 가장 중요한 부분에 주의를 기울일 수 있도록 주의 가중치를 계산합니다.
And the goal for decoupling from RNNs is to produce a more general attention mechanism
그리고 RNN에서 분리하는 목표는 보다 일반적인 주의 메커니즘을 생성하는 것입니다.
that's not confined to that recurrent structure. So we need a modified procedure. We still need
그것은 반복되는 구조에만 국한되지 않습니다. 따라서 수정된 절차가 필요합니다. 우리는 여전히 필요합니다
to determine the weight space on the context that indicate the elements to attend to, and then we
주의를 기울여야 할 요소를 나타내는 컨텍스트의 가중치 공간을 결정한 다음
need to apply these weights to enhance attendant features. Now we're going to need a new set of
수행자 기능을 향상하려면 이러한 가중치를 적용해야 합니다. 이제 우리는 새로운 세트가 필요합니다.
notation for this because the notation that we've been using is highly coupled with
왜냐하면 우리가 사용해왔던 표기법이 다음과 밀접하게 연관되어 있기 때문입니다.
the RNN structure, right, with hidden states and context vectors and all of that. Where we're
오른쪽, 숨겨진 상태와 컨텍스트 벡터 등이 포함된 RNN 구조입니다. 어디에서
going to use instead is the key value query notation, and this is the notation also used
대신 사용할 것은 키 값 쿼리 표기법이며, 이 표기법도 사용됩니다.
in the attention is all you need paper, and it reinforces the notion that we're working with
주의를 기울이는 것은 종이가 필요한 전부이며 우리가 작업하고 있는 개념을 강화합니다.
deep neural networks where we observe the superposition of features. So we're going to think
특징의 중첩을 관찰하는 심층 신경망. 그래서 우리는 생각해 볼 것입니다
of these keys, values and queries and outputs as just generic or abstract vectors that we're not
이러한 키, 값, 쿼리 및 출력은 우리가 아닌 일반 또는 추상 벡터로 표시됩니다.
going to associate meaning to right now. So that's exactly what we're going to do for now,
지금 당장에 의미를 연관시키겠습니다. 이것이 바로 지금 우리가 하려는 일입니다.
is just think of them as abstract vectors. Okay, so I've just drawn the attention mechanism here,
단지 그것들을 추상적인 벡터로 생각하면 됩니다. 좋습니다. 여기에 주의 메커니즘을 그렸습니다.
but with the key value and query notation. So the idea here is we're going to find the alignment
하지만 키 값과 쿼리 표기법을 사용합니다. 여기서 아이디어는 우리가 정렬을 찾는 것입니다.
or compatibility of the keys, so the k is here, with a query. We calculate the alignment using
또는 키의 호환성이므로 쿼리와 함께 k가 여기에 있습니다. 우리는 다음을 사용하여 정렬을 계산합니다.
an attention function. We saw before that we could do this using a feedforward network,
주의 기능. 우리는 이전에 피드포워드 네트워크를 사용하여 이 작업을 수행할 수 있다는 것을 보았습니다.
but there's multiple ways to do this. We're going to keep this just generic for now.
하지만 이를 수행하는 방법에는 여러 가지가 있습니다. 지금은 이것을 일반적인 것으로 유지하겠습니다.
Then these alignment scores are normalized to produce the attention weights,
그런 다음 이러한 정렬 점수를 정규화하여 주의 가중치를 생성합니다.
and then we use those attention weights right to scale the different values to produce an output
그런 다음 해당 주의 가중치를 사용하여 다양한 값을 조정하여 출력을 생성합니다.
vector. Now we can do this with multiple queries because we're trying to move away from this recurrent
벡터. 이제 우리는 반복되는 쿼리에서 벗어나려고 하기 때문에 여러 쿼리로 이 작업을 수행할 수 있습니다.
structure where the previous query is not dependent on the next query,
이전 쿼리가 다음 쿼리에 종속되지 않는 구조
which is what it was with the RNN structure, right, where these queries, so to speak,
이것이 바로 RNN 구조의 경우였습니다. 맞습니다. 말하자면 이러한 쿼리는
where the hidden states of the decoder, we're moving away from that. So we can calculate the
디코더의 숨겨진 상태가 있는 곳에서 우리는 그것으로부터 멀어지고 있습니다. 그래서 우리는
queries and keys potentially at the same time, as long as we set our attention function up correctly,
주의 기능을 올바르게 설정하는 한 쿼리와 키가 동시에 동시에 발생할 수 있습니다.
or in a way that can leverage this. So here the goal, again, is still to find the alignment
또는 이를 활용할 수 있는 방식으로. 따라서 여기서도 목표는 여전히 정렬을 찾는 것입니다.
or compatibility between keys and queries to scale the values, and now we're producing three
또는 키와 쿼리 간의 호환성을 통해 값을 확장할 수 있으며 이제 세 가지를 생성하고 있습니다.
outputs that correspond to the three queries that we're doing. Now at this point, let's talk about
우리가 수행 중인 세 가지 쿼리에 해당하는 출력입니다. 이제 이 시점에서 이야기해보자.
where those keys, values, and queries are coming from, and this is where the term self-attention
해당 키, 값 및 쿼리가 어디에서 나오는지, 여기서 self-attention이라는 용어가 사용됩니다.
and cross-attention come in. For self-attention, keys, values, and queries are all derived from
그리고 Cross-Attention이 들어옵니다. Self-Attention의 경우 키, 값, 쿼리는 모두 다음에서 파생됩니다.
the same source, so an arbitrary input x, let's say, that goes through an arbitrary transformation
동일한 소스이므로 임의의 입력 x가 임의의 변환을 거친다고 가정해 보겠습니다.
to produce these keys, values, and queries. Now for cross-attention, the keys and values come from
이러한 키, 값 및 쿼리를 생성합니다. 이제 교차주의를 위해 키와 값은 다음에서 나옵니다.
one source, and the queries are derived from a separate source. Now it doesn't matter where they
하나의 소스이며 쿼리는 별도의 소스에서 파생됩니다. 이제 그들이 어디에 있든 상관없어
come from, because they are all then passed into the attention function, which is agnostic to
왜냐하면 그것들은 모두 어텐션 함수로 전달되기 때문입니다.
what the keys, values, and queries are or where they come from. But this is where this notion
키, 값, 쿼리가 무엇인지 또는 어디서 왔는지. 그러나 이것이 바로 이 개념이 있는 곳입니다.
of self-attention and cross-attention comes from, as in it indicates the separation of the sources
Self-attention과 Cross-attention은 소스가 분리되어 있음을 나타냄으로써 발생합니다.
for the keys, values, and the queries. Now in terms of implementation of this decoupled
키, 값 및 쿼리의 경우. 이제 이 분리된 구현 측면에서
attention mechanism, the attention is all you need implemented it with two properties. The first is
어텐션 메커니즘에서는 어텐션만 두 가지 속성으로 구현하면 됩니다. 첫 번째는
the choice for the attention function, which was the skilled dot product. Now this is a good
숙련된 내적인 주의 함수에 대한 선택입니다. 이제 이건 좋은거야
representation of compatibility, it's fast, and it's interpretable, it's also parallelizable across
호환성을 표현하며 빠르고 해석이 가능하며 병렬화도 가능합니다.
all queries, so we can leverage GPUs. We also scale this dot product for stable
모든 쿼리를 처리하므로 GPU를 활용할 수 있습니다. 우리는 또한 이 내적을 안정적으로 확장합니다.
self-max gradients in high dimensions. Now the other property is a common dimension for keys,
높은 차원의 자체 최대 그래디언트. 이제 다른 속성은 키에 대한 공통 차원입니다.
values, and queries. Now this is a requirement for the dot product, we can't dot product to
값, 쿼리. 이제 이것은 내적에 대한 요구사항입니다. 우리는 내적을 계산할 수 없습니다.
vectors of different sizes, but it also simplifies the transformer architecture, which we'll talk
다양한 크기의 벡터를 사용할 수 있지만 트랜스포머 아키텍처도 단순화합니다.
about later, with predictable attention output shapes, and it just provides more consistent
대략 나중에 예측 가능한 주의 출력 형태를 사용하여 보다 일관성 있는 결과를 제공합니다.
hidden state dimensions for easier model analysis. So now back to this attention diagram,
더 쉬운 모델 분석을 위한 숨겨진 상태 치수. 이제 이 주의 다이어그램으로 돌아가서,
we've added in these two properties, first is we see the shared dimension for the keys,
우리는 이 두 가지 속성을 추가했습니다. 먼저 키의 공유 차원을 확인하고
values, and queries, as well as the output vector o, and we've now specified the choice for the
값, 쿼리 및 출력 벡터 o에 대한 선택 사항을 지정했습니다.
attention function, which is the dot product between each query and each key scaled by the
Attention 함수는 각 쿼리와 각 키 사이의 내적입니다.
square root of the shared dimension, dk. Now we can calculate these dot products in parallel
공유 차원의 제곱근, dk. 이제 우리는 이러한 내적을 병렬로 계산할 수 있습니다
with matrix multiplications, so we can group all the keys into a matrix k, group all the queries
행렬 곱셈을 사용하면 모든 키를 행렬 k로 그룹화하고 모든 쿼리를 그룹화할 수 있습니다.
into a matrix q, and simply do a matrix multiplication, because this is doing the exact same thing as
행렬 q에 넣고 단순히 행렬 곱셈을 하면 됩니다. 왜냐하면 이것은 다음과 똑같은 일을 하기 때문입니다.
doing a dot product between each key and each query. We can do the same thing for the values,
각 키와 각 쿼리 사이에 내적을 수행합니다. 값에 대해서도 동일한 작업을 수행할 수 있습니다.
and put all of the attention weights also in a matrix, so we can do another matrix multiplication
그리고 모든 attention 가중치를 행렬에 넣습니다. 그러면 또 다른 행렬 곱셈을 할 수 있습니다.
to produce the matrix o, the outputs. Now the reason that this is really useful is because
출력인 행렬 o를 생성합니다. 이것이 정말 유용한 이유는 다음과 같습니다.
it's highly concurrent on modern hardware, and we independently calculate each query.
최신 하드웨어에서는 동시성이 높으며 각 쿼리를 독립적으로 계산합니다.
Hi, so I'm going to take over from Aveline to do the next portion of this presentation.
안녕하세요. 이 프리젠테이션의 다음 부분을 진행하기 위해 Aveline의 일을 제가 대신하겠습니다.
I'm going to talk to you really quickly about the multi-head attention, which builds on the
나는 다중 머리 주의에 대해 매우 빠르게 이야기하겠습니다.
mechanism Aveline just explained. I'll then go into a little bit of a talk about what
메커니즘 Aveline이 방금 설명했습니다. 그럼 내용에 대해 조금 이야기해보겠습니다.
transformers are doing and what that architecture looks like. We'll then progress into a little
트랜스포머가 하고 있는 일과 그 아키텍처가 어떤 모습인지 알아보겠습니다. 그런 다음 조금 더 진행하겠습니다.
bit more of an implementational focus, and take you through how you might implement a
구현에 좀 더 중점을 두고 구현 방법을 안내합니다.
transformer yourself, and then hopefully throughout this process I'd like to clear up some misconceptions
자신을 변화시키고 이 과정을 통해 몇 가지 오해를 바로잡고 싶습니다.
about the transformer that come up colloquially, just because of people's understanding about the
구어체로 나오는 변압기에 대한 사람들의 이해 때문에
notation and how it's presented commonly. So with that said, I'm going to jump into the first
표기법과 그것이 일반적으로 어떻게 표시되는지. 그럼 저는 첫 번째로 뛰어들겠습니다.
misconception that arises about transformers, and this has to do with the attention mechanism
변압기에 대해 발생하는 오해는 주의 메커니즘과 관련이 있습니다.
Aveline just outlined. So this is a misconception about what transformers are doing, and there's
Aveline이 방금 설명했습니다. 따라서 이것은 트랜스포머가 하는 일에 대한 오해입니다.
this common idea that because of the terminology that being queries, keys, and values, people think
쿼리, 키, 값이라는 용어 때문에 사람들이 생각하는 일반적인 생각은
that this is doing some sort of vector similarity search. And because this notation is very
이것은 일종의 벡터 유사성 검색을 수행하고 있다는 것입니다. 그리고 이 표기법은 매우 중요하기 때문에
convenient, a lot of people will have reference for what a database might do, or a dictionary,
편리하게도 많은 사람들이 데이터베이스나 사전이 수행할 수 있는 작업에 대한 참고 자료를 갖게 될 것입니다.
where you look up something that is similar and then grab the corresponding value. People get
비슷한 것을 찾은 다음 해당 값을 가져오는 곳입니다. 사람들은
overly attached to this, and it's really great to introduce users to the notion of I guess a
이것에 지나치게 집착하고 있으며 사용자에게 '나는 추측한다'라는 개념을 소개하는 것이 정말 좋습니다.
similarity inner product using this definition. That being said, people don't know how to look
이 정의를 사용한 유사성 내적. 그러고 보면 사람들은 외모를 모른다.
past it, and this arises with the issue of people not understanding where we're getting our values
이를 지나쳐 사람들이 우리의 가치를 어디서 얻는지 이해하지 못하는 문제로 인해 발생합니다.
from, and then what this transformer or attention mechanism when we go about learning it is actually
그런 다음 우리가 학습할 때 실제로 이 변환기 또는 주의 메커니즘은 무엇입니까?
learning. So the question arises, are we learning something that is parametric where the meaning
학습. 그래서 질문이 생깁니다. 우리는 의미가 있는 매개변수적인 것을 배우고 있습니까?
is distilled into a preset number of parameters or weights, or is it non-parametric like you'd see
미리 설정된 수의 매개변수나 가중치로 증류됩니다. 아니면 보시다시피 비모수적인가요?
with a database where you're just storing embedded representations that you can then look into.
나중에 조사할 수 있는 내장된 표현을 저장하는 데이터베이스를 사용합니다.
What I'm going to tell you is that the transformer is a parametric process through and through.
제가 말씀드리고 싶은 것은 변환기가 철저하게 파라메트릭 프로세스라는 것입니다.
There are systems or further implementations that have been proposed like RAG, where you
RAG처럼 제안된 시스템이나 추가 구현이 있습니다.
augment the transformer process by retrieving information that kind of muddies this, and they
이런 종류의 혼란스러운 정보를 검색하여 변환기 프로세스를 강화합니다.
actually do use dictionaries to grab that information. But for today, we're just talking
실제로 해당 정보를 얻기 위해 사전을 사용합니다. 하지만 오늘은 그냥 얘기만 하자
about the transformer in its vanilla format. And in this situation, we are just learning
바닐라 형식의 변압기에 대해. 그리고 이 상황에서 우리는 단지 배우고 있는 중입니다.
parametrically. So talking about what is being learned, Aveline has mentioned that the attention
매개변수적으로. 따라서 학습되는 내용에 대해 이야기하면서 Aveline은 주의력이 중요하다고 언급했습니다.
mechanism that Vaswani and his colleagues put forward is this scaled dot product attention.
Vaswani와 그의 동료들이 제시한 메커니즘은 이 스케일링된 내적 관심입니다.
But when we look at this, no matter where we're coming from, whether that self-attention where
하지만 우리가 이것을 보면, 우리가 어디에서 왔는지, Self-Attention이 어디에서 왔는지에 관계없이
you're getting everything from a single input where you're attending to yourself, or cross
당신은 자신에게 주의를 기울이는 단일 입력에서 모든 것을 얻거나 교차합니다.
attention where you have an arbitrary input attending to another input to generate the
다른 입력을 생성하기 위해 임의의 입력이 있는 경우 주의하세요.
queries, keys, and values. Regardless of this, the dot product attention is just an operation.
쿼리, 키, 값. 그럼에도 불구하고 내적 주의는 단지 연산일 뿐입니다.
It's not learning any parameters as part of that, which means we need to look elsewhere to try to
그 일부로 어떤 매개변수도 학습하지 않습니다. 즉, 다른 곳에서 학습을 시도해야 함을 의미합니다.
figure out what we're going to be learning. And this is where the real power of the transformer
우리가 무엇을 배울 것인지 알아내세요. 그리고 이것이 바로 변압기의 진정한 힘이 되는 곳입니다.
comes in, is we want to learn linear maps or weight matrices that are going to take our arbitrary
들어와서, 우리는 임의의 값을 취할 선형 맵이나 가중치 행렬을 배우고 싶습니다.
input, no matter where it's coming from, and transform that into the independent parts that
입력이 어디서 나오든 상관없이 이를 독립된 부분으로 변환하여
will feed into this attention mechanism. Those are the queries, the keys, and the values.
이 주의 메커니즘에 영향을 미칠 것입니다. 이는 쿼리, 키 및 값입니다.
So to produce the queries, let's look at the self-attention example. We have our input x,
쿼리를 생성하기 위해 self-attention 예제를 살펴보겠습니다. 우리는 입력 x를 가지고 있습니다.
which again, since we've got this polysemanticity of the representations in a deep neural network,
다시 말하지만, 우리는 심층 신경망에서 표현의 다의미성을 얻었기 때문에
we're just going to consider an arbitrary vector or an arbitrary sequence of vectors in the situation
우리는 상황에 따라 임의의 벡터 또는 임의의 벡터 시퀀스를 고려해 보겠습니다.
where we look at all of x. And what we do is we multiply that with a weights matrix, and these
x를 모두 보는 곳입니다. 그리고 우리가 하는 일은 그것에 가중치 행렬을 곱하는 것입니다.
are parameters that we're learning for the network that'll make us produce queries that are useful
유용한 쿼리를 생성할 수 있도록 네트워크에 대해 학습 중인 매개변수입니다.
to then grab the relevant information. We likewise do this to inform what the keys are,
그런 다음 관련 정보를 가져옵니다. 마찬가지로 키가 무엇인지 알려주기 위해 이 작업을 수행합니다.
and again, we're looking at that similarity between the keys and queries, and we want those to be
그리고 다시, 우리는 키와 쿼리 사이의 유사성을 살펴보고 있으며, 우리는 이러한 유사성을 원합니다.
distinct depending on what needs to be attended to. And then finally, the values. So when we're
무엇을 처리해야 하는지에 따라 구분됩니다. 그리고 마지막으로 가치관입니다. 그래서 우리가 할 때
actually talking about attention, a lot of times, because this notation is overloaded, and you'll
실제로 주의에 대해 여러 번 이야기합니다. 왜냐하면 이 표기법은 과부하가 걸리기 때문입니다.
see the multi-head attention that we'll talk about in a couple of slides takes in keys, queries,
키, 쿼리,
values, but the attention mechanism it calls also takes in keys, values, and queries.
하지만 호출되는 주의 메커니즘은 키, 값 및 쿼리도 받아들입니다.
Because they're overloaded so much, people think, well, the input in the situation
너무 과부하가 걸리기 때문에 사람들은 상황에 대한 입력이
is the exact same as the value. So if you have a query and a value, they could be the same,
값과 완전히 동일합니다. 따라서 쿼리와 값이 있는 경우에는 동일할 수 있습니다.
but while they could theoretically, when you're actually learning this through the process of
이론적으로는 그럴 수 있지만 실제로는 다음 과정을 통해 이를 배울 수 있습니다.
optimization, these weights matrices are going to learn different things. So our keys and queries
최적화를 통해 이러한 가중치 행렬은 다양한 것을 학습하게 됩니다. 그래서 우리의 키와 쿼리는
will be aligned, yes, but when we talk about self-attention, it's not just doing a attention
네, 그렇습니다. 하지만 우리가 self-attention에 관해 이야기할 때, 그것은 단순히 주의를 기울이는 것이 아닙니다.
between its input and itself. These are independent, or sorry, they are dependent on one another
입력과 자체 사이. 이들은 독립적입니다. 또는 죄송합니다. 서로 의존하고 있습니다.
because they come from the same source, but they have been learned to have different representations
왜냐하면 그들은 같은 근원에서 나왔지만 서로 다른 표현을 갖도록 학습되었기 때문입니다.
that can then ask each other questions of, are you an important feature that I want to be using
그런 다음 서로에게 질문할 수 있습니다. 내가 사용하고 싶은 중요한 기능이 있습니까?
to carry that information forward? So now that we have a little bit more
그 정보를 전달하기 위해? 이제 조금 더 남았으니
intuition about where our values are coming from, where our keys and queries are also coming from,
우리의 가치가 어디에서 왔는지, 키와 쿼리도 어디에서 왔는지에 대한 직관,
and we've talked about what is being learned in this process, I'm going to move into the idea
우리는 이 과정에서 무엇을 배우고 있는지에 대해 이야기했습니다. 이제 아이디어로 넘어가겠습니다.
of multi-head attention, which builds on top of that original attention, and it's what the paper
원래의 관심을 바탕으로 여러 사람의 주의를 기울이는 것이 논문의 내용입니다.
really leverages to get this increased performance. So as I've mentioned a couple of times, it builds
실제로 이러한 향상된 성능을 얻기 위해 활용합니다. 그래서 제가 몇 번 언급했듯이,
on top of the scaled dot product attention that the authors implement. It's an extension of this
저자가 구현한 스케일링된 도트 제품 주의 위에 있습니다. 이것의 연장선이군요
generalized attention mechanism outlined previously in our presentation, and the real idea here is
이전 프레젠테이션에서 설명한 일반화된 주의 메커니즘과 실제 아이디어는 다음과 같습니다.
that it's going to leverage multiple heads to attend to different things. So like we saw with
여러 머리를 활용하여 다양한 일을 처리하게 될 것입니다. 그래서 우리가 본 것처럼
the recurrent neural network situation earlier, having a singular context that only takes one
이전의 반복 신경망 상황은 하나만 취하는 단일 컨텍스트를 가졌습니다.
perspective about what is important, even if we're doing it each time, which we've kind of introduced
매번 그렇게 하더라도 중요한 것이 무엇인지에 대한 관점을 소개했습니다.
with this attention mechanism, is still an informational bottleneck. So even though we've
이 주의 메커니즘을 사용하면 여전히 정보 병목 현상이 발생합니다. 그래서 우리가 그랬음에도 불구하고
gotten better because we've introduced attention, we can make it even better than that by having
우리가 관심을 도입했기 때문에 더 좋아졌습니다.
different sub-representations, and I'll get into how we learn these different representations
다양한 하위 표현을 학습하고 이러한 다양한 표현을 학습하는 방법에 대해 알아보겠습니다.
in a minute. But the main idea is if we can look at the data from different angles, we can have the
잠시 후. 하지만 주요 아이디어는 데이터를 다른 각도에서 볼 수 있다면 다음과 같은 결과를 얻을 수 있다는 것입니다.
model learn to jointly attend to different views of that data, so that when we have the decoder
모델은 해당 데이터의 다양한 관점에 공동으로 주의를 기울이는 방법을 학습하므로 디코더가 있을 때
finally go to access that information, it can take on a view and be comfortable that that information
마침내 해당 정보에 액세스하면 해당 정보를 볼 수 있고 편안해질 수 있습니다.
is there, that it needs to decode the next token or element of the arbitrary sequence.
즉, 임의 시퀀스의 다음 토큰이나 요소를 디코딩해야 합니다.
So I'm going to give a little bit of intuition for why multi-head
그래서 왜 다중 헤드인지에 대해 약간의 직관을 제공하겠습니다.
attention is even needed in the first place. When we go through the top half of the attention block,
처음부터 주의가 필요합니다. Attention 블록의 위쪽 절반을 통과하면
so we're talking about taking the attention weights and multiplying it with the values,
그래서 우리는 어텐션 가중치를 취하고 여기에 값을 곱하는 것에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
what you'll notice is because we're doing this as a multiplication in addition or a matrix
여러분이 주목하게 될 것은 우리가 이것을 덧셈의 곱셈이나 행렬로 하고 있기 때문입니다.
multiplication when you put everything together and parallelize it, we multiply the values,
곱셈 모든 것을 함께 모아서 병렬화하면 값을 곱합니다.
but then we sum through the dimension of the values. So this is corresponding with the keys
그런 다음 값의 차원을 통해 합산합니다. 그래서 이것은 키와 일치합니다
and the actual values themselves. So from one sequence, we're summing through based on a singular
그리고 실제 값 자체. 따라서 하나의 시퀀스에서 단수를 기반으로 합산합니다.
view. And since we summed through, we've lost resolution about what is important. Essentially,
보다. 그리고 요약을 해보니 무엇이 중요한지에 대한 결정력을 잃어버렸습니다. 본질적으로,
we've committed to one perspective. And the goal with multi-head attention is to learn multiple
우리는 하나의 관점을 고수했습니다. 그리고 Multi-head attention의 목표는 여러 가지를 배우는 것입니다.
sets of weights. So we have one attention head that has one set of weights to produce the keys,
가중치 세트. 그래서 우리는 키를 생성하기 위한 하나의 가중치 세트를 가진 하나의 어텐션 헤드를 가지고 있습니다.
values, and queries given an input, and then another head that has a different separate
입력이 제공된 값 및 쿼리, 그리고 다른 별도의 헤드를 가진 다른 헤드
set of weights to learn a different set of queries, keys, and values, etc., etc. The paper
다양한 쿼리, 키, 값 등 세트를 학습하기 위한 가중치 세트. 논문
actually extends this to learn eight separate heads and modern architectures that use the
실제로 이것을 확장하여 8개의 개별 헤드와 최신 아키텍처를 학습합니다.
transformer have much, much, much more number of heads. And the real goal here is to learn
변압기에는 훨씬 더 많은 수의 헤드가 있습니다. 여기서 진짜 목표는 배우는 것입니다.
sub-representations that give you different perspectives on the data so we can learn a
데이터에 대한 다양한 관점을 제공하는 하위 표현을 통해 우리는
richer representation and pack all that context together about how each element in a sequence
더 풍부한 표현을 제공하고 시퀀스의 각 요소가 어떻게 작동하는지에 대한 모든 컨텍스트를 하나로 묶습니다.
relates to the other elements in that sequence, regardless of that this is the input sequence
입력 시퀀스인지 여부에 관계없이 해당 시퀀스의 다른 요소와 관련됩니다.
that has a direct meaning from the tokens or if we're further up in the network and dealing with
이는 토큰에서 직접적인 의미를 갖거나 우리가 네트워크에서 더 높은 위치에 있고 다음을 처리하는 경우
just arbitrary sequences that have positional information or semantic or grammatical information
위치 정보나 의미 또는 문법 정보를 가진 임의의 시퀀스
packed into it. So you might ask yourself, well, if we're going to add a whole bunch of different
그것에 포장. 그렇다면 여러분은 스스로에게 물어볼 수도 있습니다. 음, 우리가 다양한 기능을 모두 추가할 것인지
attention heads, aren't we going to increase the computational cost dramatically? And you'd be
주목하세요, 계산 비용이 극적으로 증가하지 않을까요? 그리고 당신은
correct if we didn't take extra precautions. Now what the authors find as a kind of compromise to
추가 예방 조치를 취하지 않았다면 정확합니다. 이제 저자가 일종의 타협점으로 찾은 것은
this is if they shrink the dimension of the sub-representation, so we go down to a smaller
이는 하위 표현의 크기를 축소하는 경우이므로 더 작은 크기로 이동합니다.
dimensional space for each attention head, we can reduce or compress the information given a certain
각 주의 머리에 대한 차원 공간을 사용하여 특정 주어진 정보를 줄이거나 압축할 수 있습니다.
lens to make it more useful for that perspective, but have lower computational cost. And what they
렌즈를 사용하면 해당 관점에 더 유용하지만 계산 비용은 더 낮습니다. 그리고 그들은 무엇을
find is if they divide the total dimension of the model, since we have that imposed fixed dimension
find는 고정된 차원을 부과했기 때문에 모델의 전체 차원을 나누는 경우입니다.
that Aveline mentioned earlier, by the number of heads, we end up with a smaller dimensional
앞서 Aveline이 언급한 것처럼 머리 수에 따라 차원이 더 작아집니다.
subspace that still lets us compute in roughly the same amount of time as if we had a single head,
마치 머리가 하나인 것처럼 대략 같은 시간 안에 계산할 수 있는 부분 공간입니다.
but we can get a lot more rich information just because that compression isn't actually by that
하지만 압축이 실제로는 그렇지 않기 때문에 훨씬 더 풍부한 정보를 얻을 수 있습니다.
big of a factor. So a visual representation of what happens here is say we have some
큰 요인입니다. 여기서 일어나는 일을 시각적으로 표현하면 다음과 같습니다.
source that's going to flow into our weights matrices, and I haven't rendered that on the
가중치 행렬로 유입될 소스가 있는데 아직 렌더링하지 않았습니다.
slide here, but just imagine it's coming from the left, it would then flow through these weight
여기로 슬라이드하세요. 왼쪽에서 나온다고 상상해 보세요. 그러면 이 무게를 통해 흐를 것입니다.
matrices that are for each head, produce the keys, values, and queries, and then out of that each
각 헤드에 대한 행렬은 키, 값 및 쿼리를 생성한 다음 그로부터 각각
attention head will produce a separate output matrix, and this is going to represent the,
attention head는 별도의 출력 매트릭스를 생성하며 이는 다음을 나타냅니다.
it's going to be dimension of t by dk, t referring to the number of elements in the decoding sequence,
그것은 t x dk의 차원이 될 것입니다. t는 디코딩 시퀀스의 요소 수를 나타냅니다.
or where the queries are coming from in the first place. Now if you recall that we have this
또는 쿼리가 처음에 어디서 나오는지. 이제 우리에게 이것이 있다는 것을 기억한다면
constant imposed dimensionality of the model, you might look at the fact that we have multiple
모델에 일정하게 부과된 차원이 있는 경우, 우리가 여러 가지 차원을 가지고 있다는 사실을 볼 수 있습니다.
outputs now and say well that's not going to fly with our understanding that the model has
지금 출력하고 모델이
consistent dimension throughout it. We need something that the rest of the model is set up to use
전체적으로 일관된 차원. 모델의 나머지 부분이 사용하도록 설정된 것이 필요합니다.
and understand. So you'd be correct in that assumption, and what we finally want to do is
그리고 이해합니다. 따라서 그 가정은 옳을 것입니다. 그리고 우리가 최종적으로 하고 싶은 것은
introduce a final weights matrix that is also learned as a set of parameters to kind of pack up
일종의 팩업을 위한 매개변수 세트로도 학습되는 최종 가중치 행렬을 도입합니다.
that rich amount of context from all these different views into the problem,
문제에 대한 다양한 관점에서 얻은 풍부한 맥락,
into a singular output. So we can catenate all of the heads and then do a matrix multiplication
단일 출력으로. 따라서 우리는 모든 머리를 연결한 다음 행렬 곱셈을 수행할 수 있습니다.
of that finally with this weight 0, which represents the weights for this output transformation,
마지막으로 이 출력 변환의 가중치를 나타내는 가중치 0을 사용하여
and it's going to bring us back to that proper dimension of the model. So from dk times the
그리고 그것은 우리를 모델의 적절한 차원으로 다시 데려갈 것입니다. 그래서 dk 시대부터
number of heads to the d model. So we've talked now about multi-head attention, and that's kind of
d 모델의 헤드 수. 이제 우리는 다중 헤드 어텐션(multi-head attention)에 대해 이야기했습니다.
the understanding that we've just went through and why it's so important. Now I want to talk about
우리가 방금 겪은 이해와 그것이 왜 그렇게 중요한지. 이제 나는 이야기하고 싶다.
how the transformer architecture uses that to escape the problems that RNNs had. So I'm going
변환기 아키텍처가 이를 사용하여 RNN의 문제를 탈출하는 방법. 그래서 나는 갈거야
to say that the attention architecture in the transformer, this multi-head idea, is leveraged
즉, 다중 헤드 아이디어인 트랜스포머의 어텐션 아키텍처가 활용된다고 말할 수 있습니다.
in three different ways in the transformer. One is it does self-attention in the encoder,
변압기에서는 세 가지 다른 방식으로 작동합니다. 하나는 인코더에서 self-attention을 수행한다는 것입니다.
the next is that it does masked self-attention in the decoder, and finally we have that auto
다음은 디코더에서 마스킹된 self-attention을 수행한다는 것입니다. 마지막으로 우리는 자동을 갖게 되었습니다.
regressive element where we're doing the encoder-decoder cross-attention. Because we're going through
인코더-디코더 교차 주의를 수행하는 회귀 요소입니다. 우리는 겪고 있으니까
the process of decoding a sequence and we need to produce token at a time, we do end up with this
시퀀스를 디코딩하는 프로세스가 필요하고 한 번에 토큰을 생성해야 하는데, 결국 이렇게 됩니다.
auto regressive element that's still there, but the goal is to use these new self-attention elements
자동 회귀 요소는 여전히 존재하지만 목표는 이러한 새로운 self-attention 요소를 사용하는 것입니다.
that I'll explain a little bit more in a second to offload a lot of that work so that the computer
많은 작업을 오프로드하여 컴퓨터가
can run it in parallel and we do the minimal amount of time as possible kind of going from one
병렬로 실행할 수 있으며 하나에서 시작하여 가능한 한 최소한의 시간을 수행합니다.
sequence to the next sequence, or from one element of the sequence to the next element.
시퀀스를 다음 시퀀스로 이동하거나 시퀀스의 한 요소에서 다음 요소로 이동합니다.
So recall that we've got a custom context per layer, so we've got different heads per layer of the
따라서 우리는 레이어마다 사용자 정의 컨텍스트를 가지고 있으므로 레이어마다 다른 헤드를 가지고 있다는 것을 기억하십시오.
architecture, and we want to reduce the amount of time that's going into that. So what you might
아키텍처에 소요되는 시간을 줄이고 싶습니다. 그래서 당신은 무엇을 할 수 있습니까?
say is whereas the recurrent neural network architecture needs the previous input and we
순환 신경망 아키텍처에는 이전 입력이 필요하고 우리는
run all of them in sequence, instead let's take away the idea of this recurrence. Instead we're
모두 순서대로 실행하는 대신 이러한 반복에 대한 아이디어를 없애겠습니다. 대신 우리는
going to run the idea of self-attention on the entire input that we're looking at. So at a given
우리가 보고 있는 전체 입력에 대해 self-attention이라는 아이디어를 실행할 것입니다. 그래서 주어진 시간에
time step, the history of the model, the tokens that have already been seen, are then encoded as
그런 다음 시간 단계, 모델의 기록, 이미 본 토큰을 다음과 같이 인코딩합니다.
part of this self-attention block, and it allows the model to jointly attend to all positions of
이 self-attention 블록의 일부이며, 이를 통해 모델은 공동으로 모든 위치에 주의를 기울일 수 있습니다.
the encoder. So it doesn't need to just flow through a path of the previous hidden states,
인코더. 따라서 이전 숨겨진 상태의 경로를 따라 흐를 필요는 없으며,
but each area, because we add in a little bit of positional information at the very start,
하지만 각 영역은 처음에 약간의 위치 정보를 추가하기 때문에
can then look at all of the other elements and understand how it relates to the other
그러면 다른 모든 요소를 ​​살펴보고 그것이 다른 요소와 어떻게 관련되어 있는지 이해할 수 있습니다.
context that's there. And this embeds context about how the elements not only relate to one
거기에 있는 맥락입니다. 그리고 이는 요소가 하나의 요소와 어떻게 관련되는지에 대한 맥락을 포함합니다.
another, but then can be useful downstream. So each layers or each attention block is optimized
다른 것이지만 다운스트림에 유용할 수 있습니다. 따라서 각 레이어 또는 각 주의 블록이 최적화됩니다.
so that it's feeding forward in the network the most important information. Now the mass
그래서 가장 중요한 정보를 네트워크에 전달합니다. 이제 질량
self-attention in the decoder also eliminates this idea of dependency on the previous tokens
디코더의 self-attention은 이전 토큰에 대한 종속성 아이디어도 제거합니다.
as part of the architecture. We still have this autoregressive process, but at any single
아키텍처의 일부로. 우리는 여전히 이러한 자기회귀 과정을 갖고 있지만 어느 시점에서든
iteration of that autoregressive process, we're running with all of the previously decoded tokens.
자동 회귀 프로세스를 반복하면 이전에 디코딩된 모든 토큰을 사용하여 실행됩니다.
And instead of needing to do a complex path traversal to get that information, we treat it
그리고 해당 정보를 얻기 위해 복잡한 경로 순회를 수행할 필요 없이 이를 처리합니다.
the exact same way as the self-attention in the encoder. So we have each element look at everything
인코더의 self-attention과 완전히 동일한 방식입니다. 그래서 우리는 각 요소가 모든 것을 살펴보도록 합니다.
else that was previously there to try to inform, well, what is the context that I need to share
그 외에는 제가 공유해야 할 맥락이 무엇인지 알리기 위해 이전에 있었던 것입니다.
to generate this token? And at this point, since we've decoupled from the recurrent structure,
이 토큰을 생성하려면? 그리고 이 시점에서 우리는 순환 구조에서 분리되었으므로
we're just talking about the next token that would be produced as if it was a single output.
우리는 마치 단일 출력인 것처럼 생성될 다음 토큰에 대해서만 이야기하고 있습니다.
Now, this comes up with an issue of forward-looking bias because certain elements weren't produced
이제 특정 요소가 생산되지 않았기 때문에 미래 지향적 편견 문제가 발생합니다.
at the time that they would be actually seen, right? As you go from left to right in an encoded
실제로 볼 수 있는 순간이겠죠? 인코딩된 텍스트에서 왼쪽에서 오른쪽으로 이동하면
sequence, or a sequence that you're trying to decode, by the time you get to token three,
시퀀스 또는 디코딩하려는 시퀀스는 토큰 3에 도달할 때까지
you have not seen the information or context about token four, five, etc. So you don't want
토큰 4, 5 등에 대한 정보나 컨텍스트를 본 적이 없습니다.
those impacting how it makes its embedding. So in this situation, what we do is the authors
임베딩 방법에 영향을 미치는 요소입니다. 그래서 이런 상황에서 우리가 하는 일은 저자입니다.
introduce a notion of masking or contextual masking that blocks out the future so that you can't
마스킹 또는 상황에 맞는 마스킹이라는 개념을 도입하여 미래를 차단하여
inform the important information that you're going to express based off of future information.
미래의 정보를 바탕으로 표현하고자 하는 중요한 정보를 알려드립니다.
And what this allows us to do is still do this in parallel because we've got the entire sequence
그리고 이를 통해 우리는 이 작업을 병렬로 수행할 수 있습니다. 전체 시퀀스를 얻었기 때문입니다.
at once. And all of the queries that the model will be seeing are able to be independent of
한 번에. 그리고 모델이 보게 될 모든 쿼리는
one another because the architecture doesn't force them to have that recurrent structure.
왜냐하면 아키텍처가 반복적인 구조를 갖도록 강요하지 않기 때문입니다.
And that's the real strength of what's going on here is we've offloaded a lot of that work,
그리고 이것이 여기서 일어나고 있는 일의 진정한 강점은 우리가 그 많은 작업을 덜어냈다는 것입니다.
even though we have to do this out of aggressively, to the self-attention part.
비록 우리가 자기 관심 부분에 있어서 공격적으로 이 일을 해야 한다고 해도 말이죠.
Finally, we have the encoder-decoder cross-attention. And what this is going to allow us to do is have
마지막으로 인코더-디코더 교차 주의가 있습니다. 그리고 이를 통해 우리가 할 수 있는 일은
our decoder look at the information from the encoder and extract and pull in the relevant
우리의 디코더는 인코더의 정보를 보고 관련 정보를 추출하고 가져옵니다.
context to inform how it's going to continue decoding. So we still have that encoder that's
디코딩을 계속하는 방법을 알려주는 컨텍스트입니다. 그래서 우리는 여전히 인코더를 가지고 있습니다.
going to take all the information and press it into useful context in a latent space,
모든 정보를 수집하여 잠재 공간의 유용한 컨텍스트에 적용할 것입니다.
and then the decoder that's going to exploit that. But the area between the two where we're
그리고 그것을 활용할 디코더입니다. 하지만 우리가 있는 둘 사이의 영역은
actually doing calculations are regressively is minimized. And that's the real essence of why
실제로 계산을 수행하는 것은 회귀적으로 최소화됩니다. 그리고 그것이 바로 그 이유의 진짜 본질입니다
the transformer is so much more efficient. So the authors further motivate this with kind of a
변압기는 훨씬 더 효율적입니다. 그래서 저자들은 일종의 동기를 부여합니다.
why self-attention section. If I was to summarize it quickly, they break their analysis down into
왜 self-attention 섹션인가요? 빨리 요약하자면 그들은 분석을 다음과 같이 분류합니다.
three components. One is the complexity per layer, one is the sequential number of operations that
세 가지 구성 요소. 하나는 레이어당 복잡성이고, 하나는 순차적인 작업 수입니다.
needed to be run, and the final one is the maximum path length. So working right to left,
실행해야 하며 마지막은 최대 경로 길이입니다. 그래서 오른쪽에서 왼쪽으로 작업하고,
I'm going to talk about the maximum path length. First, this comes from the notion of the recurrent
최대 경로 길이에 대해 이야기하겠습니다. 첫째, 이는 반복이라는 개념에서 비롯됩니다.
neural network, where to get information about your hidden state from your dependencies, you
종속성에서 숨겨진 상태에 대한 정보를 얻을 수 있는 신경망
actually needed to flow through the previous hidden states. So at any single time, your time
실제로 이전 숨겨진 상태를 통과해야 했습니다. 그러니 언제든지, 당신의 시간
complexity is based on how long that path is, or the number of elements you've seen. In the
복잡성은 해당 경로의 길이 또는 본 요소 수에 따라 달라집니다. 에서
self-attention block, because we've encoded that understanding of position into it, and our architecture
self-attention 블록은 위치에 대한 이해와 아키텍처를 인코딩했기 때문입니다.
doesn't enforce any type of dependency here, we don't need to go looking for that information
여기서는 어떤 유형의 종속성도 적용하지 않으므로 해당 정보를 찾을 필요가 없습니다.
elsewhere. It will be encoded into the position that I'm actually referring to at the time of
다른 곳. 실제로 제가 언급하고 있는 위치로 인코딩됩니다.
doing the calculation. So the maximum path length is considered constant. As far as sequential
계산을 하고 있어요. 따라서 최대 경로 길이는 일정한 것으로 간주됩니다. 순차적인 만큼
operations go, this is just referring to how much can be parallelized. So again, because we've removed
작업이 진행되는 경우 이는 병렬화할 수 있는 양을 나타냅니다. 다시 말하지만, 우리는 제거했기 때문에
that recurrent operation, even though we're doing it iteration by iteration at a single iteration,
반복되는 작업은 단일 반복에서 반복을 수행하더라도
it's a fixed or constant time, because I'm not dependent on flowing through the model state at
이는 고정된 또는 일정한 시간입니다. 왜냐하면 모델 상태를 통과하는 흐름에 의존하지 않기 때문입니다.
a time. Finally, we have the complexity per layer, and for self-attention, since we've talked about
시간. 마지막으로, 레이어당 복잡성과 self-attention에 대해 이야기했습니다.
this at length as a scale dot product that we can then use as a matrix multiplication,
이것은 행렬 곱셈으로 사용할 수 있는 스케일 내적의 길이입니다.
we end up with a time complexity of n squared d, just because we're doing these matrix
우리는 이 행렬을 수행하기 때문에 n 제곱 d의 시간 복잡도를 갖게 됩니다.
multiplications per iteration through the network, and this is per layer. So that explains what's
네트워크를 통한 반복당 곱셈은 레이어별로 이루어집니다. 그래서 그게 뭔지 설명해준다
going on here, and what we notice is that the self-attention mechanism on modern hardware,
여기서 우리가 주목하는 것은 최신 하드웨어의 self-attention 메커니즘입니다.
where we can really use that concurrency that's been so optimized for doing matrix multiplications,
행렬 곱셈을 수행하는 데 최적화된 동시성을 실제로 사용할 수 있는 곳은
we end up with a lower computational complexity, a greater amount of the computation that can
우리는 계산 복잡도를 낮추고 더 많은 양의 계산을 할 수 있게 됩니다.
actually be parallelized, and we end up with a representation that encodes the positional
실제로 병렬화되고 위치를 인코딩하는 표현으로 끝납니다.
and referential information about each element with relationship to each other in the sequence.
그리고 시퀀스 내에서 서로 관계가 있는 각 요소에 대한 참조 정보를 포함합니다.
So this just emphasizes the idea that this is much cheaper, and when things are cheaper,
그래서 이것은 이것이 훨씬 더 저렴하다는 생각을 강조할 뿐입니다. 그리고 물건이 더 저렴할 때,
we actually have the ability for the same cost to go deeper, which will allow us to be more powerful,
우리는 실제로 동일한 비용으로 더 깊이 들어갈 수 있는 능력을 갖고 있으며, 이를 통해 우리는 더욱 강력해질 수 있습니다.
given a fixed number of parameters. It's also faster to train, because we have the ability,
고정된 수의 매개변수가 주어졌습니다. 또한 우리에게는 능력이 있기 때문에 훈련하는 것이 더 빠릅니다.
we don't have that recurrent relationship, so when we're going through a training process,
우리는 반복되는 관계가 없으므로 훈련 과정을 거칠 때
we don't need to iteratively predict each token in a row. You can take a single sequence and just
우리는 연속적으로 각 토큰을 반복적으로 예측할 필요가 없습니다. 단일 시퀀스를 취하고
phrase it as predict the next token, and batch up based on, okay, given this input, predict the
다음 토큰을 예측한다고 표현하고, 이 입력이 주어지면 이를 기반으로 일괄 처리하여 다음 토큰을 예측합니다.
single next token, and you can run all of those in parallel. Finally, as a little bit of conversation,
단일 다음 토큰을 사용하면 모든 토큰을 병렬로 실행할 수 있습니다. 마지막으로 약간의 대화를 나누면,
when the vocabulary that you're trying to express, or the sequence length n,
표현하려는 어휘나 시퀀스 길이 n이
for a given input that you're trying to turn into another sequence,
다른 시퀀스로 변환하려는 특정 입력에 대해
is smaller than the actual dimension of your model. So the hidden representation state,
모델의 실제 치수보다 작습니다. 따라서 숨겨진 표현 상태는
which it often is when we're dealing with sequences, it's going to be much faster to
시퀀스를 다룰 때 자주 발생하는 일입니다.
use the self-attention mechanism than the recurrent one. So we also have the benefit
반복 메커니즘보다 self-attention 메커니즘을 사용합니다. 그래서 우리도 이익을 얻습니다
just by nature of the problem that people are using this for.
사람들이 이것을 사용하는 문제의 성격상.
So now that we've motivated how the transformer is going to be using these
이제 우리는 변환기가 이러한 요소를 어떻게 사용할 것인지 동기를 부여했습니다.
elements of self-attention, I'm going to talk about the architecture a little bit,
Self-Attention의 요소에 대해 아키텍처에 대해 조금 이야기하겠습니다.
and this is going to be a high-level glance. We'll get into more of the implementation details
이것은 높은 수준의 개요가 될 것입니다. 구현 세부 사항에 대해 더 자세히 알아 보겠습니다.
down the road, but if you're going to take anything from this presentation, I want it to be
하지만 이 프리젠테이션에서 무엇인가 취하고 싶다면, 그렇게 되기를 바랍니다.
the multi-head attention and why the transformer is able to decouple from the RNN and why that's
다중 헤드 주의 및 변환기가 RNN에서 분리될 수 있는 이유와 그 이유
a good thing, and also how they work together to build this overall transformer architecture.
좋은 일이며, 전체적인 트랜스포머 아키텍처를 구축하기 위해 어떻게 협력하는지도 설명합니다.
So when you hear about it in literature or presentations or just projects in general,
따라서 문헌이나 프리젠테이션 또는 일반적인 프로젝트에서 이에 대해 들으면
you understand what's going on architecturally. So given this image that I've got on the screen,
당신은 건축학적으로 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 이해합니다. 화면에 표시된 이 이미지를 보면
let's talk about what this task is. We're going from an arbitrary input sequence to an arbitrary
이 작업이 무엇인지 이야기해 봅시다. 우리는 임의의 입력 시퀀스에서 임의의 입력 시퀀스로 가고 있습니다.
decoded sequence or target sequence, and the idea is that for this model to work,
디코딩된 시퀀스 또는 대상 시퀀스이며 이 모델이 작동하려면
we need to go to a floating point dimension system. These neural networks aren't designed to work on
부동 소수점 차원 시스템으로 전환해야 합니다. 이 신경망은 작동하도록 설계되지 않았습니다.
tokens or symbols explicitly, instead they use a numerical approach. So we're going to take our
토큰이나 기호를 명시적으로 사용하는 대신 수치적 접근 방식을 사용합니다. 그래서 우리는 우리의 것을 가져갈 것입니다
input and our output, because both of them are going to flow through these encoder and decoder
입력과 출력 모두 이 인코더와 디코더를 통해 흐르기 때문입니다.
stacks, and we're going to embed them into a numerical space, right? So this goes through an
스택을 쌓아서 숫자 공간에 삽입할 것입니다. 그렇죠? 그래서 이것은 다음과 같은 과정을 거칩니다.
embedding input embedding space, sorry, an input embedding layer, let's say, and an output embedding
임베딩 입력 임베딩 공간, 죄송합니다. 입력 임베딩 레이어, 예를 들어 출력 임베딩
layer to then flow into the rest of the model. Next, these sequences will go into the process of
그런 다음 모델의 나머지 부분으로 흘러들어갑니다. 다음으로 이러한 시퀀스는
positional encoding. Now the positional encoding element of this architecture is going to weave in
위치 인코딩. 이제 이 아키텍처의 위치 인코딩 요소가 엮어질 것입니다.
or superimpose into the signal information about where the element is with reference to all the
또는 모든 요소를 ​​참조하여 요소가 어디에 있는지에 대한 신호 정보를 중첩합니다.
other elements, and this is why we're able to get rid of this recurrent relationship. We don't need
다른 요소들과 이것이 우리가 반복되는 관계를 제거할 수 있는 이유입니다. 우리는 필요하지 않습니다
the path to define what came before or what comes after, because that information is directly
이전 또는 이후에 오는 내용을 정의하는 경로입니다. 왜냐하면 해당 정보는 직접적으로
available in the representation of that element of the sequence. We then have that common encoder
시퀀스의 해당 요소를 표현하는 데 사용할 수 있습니다. 그런 다음 공통 인코더가 있습니다.
decoder architecture that we talked about earlier, and we'll zoom in on these in a second, but the
앞서 이야기한 디코더 아키텍처에 대해서는 잠시 후에 확대해 보겠습니다.
main idea is we're going to compress that information in the encoder, and then in the decoder
주요 아이디어는 해당 정보를 인코더에서 압축한 다음 디코더에서 압축한다는 것입니다.
expand it out to generate that next token flowing through the prediction head or generator at the
이를 확장하여 예측 헤드 또는 생성기를 통해 흐르는 다음 토큰을 생성합니다.
top. That prediction head will output a set of probabilities about what the token could be in a
맨 위. 해당 예측 헤드는 토큰이 무엇일 수 있는지에 대한 일련의 확률을 출력합니다.
preset vocal caporum or vocabulary that you're using to represent these sequences,
이러한 시퀀스를 표현하는 데 사용하는 미리 설정된 보컬 카포럼 또는 어휘,
and then that'll flow through a decoding procedure that'll select what the next token is given those
그런 다음 다음 토큰이 무엇인지 선택하는 디코딩 절차를 통해 흐릅니다.
probabilities, and that's the part that's auto regressive here, is that given a previous amount
확률입니다. 여기서 자동 회귀하는 부분은 이전 금액이 주어졌을 때입니다.
of decoded tokens, we're going to predict what the next token could be and use some decoding
디코딩된 토큰 중에서 다음 토큰이 무엇인지 예측하고 일부 디코딩을 사용할 것입니다.
procedure to select the one that is most likely. So zooming in on the encoder block,
가능성이 가장 높은 것을 선택하는 절차입니다. 인코더 블록을 확대하면
the encoder is essentially going to be applying this self-attention to add on context about how
인코더는 본질적으로 이 self-attention을 적용하여 어떻게 진행되는지에 대한 컨텍스트를 추가할 것입니다.
the elements relate to one another. So in a language to language or text to text task,
요소는 서로 관련되어 있습니다. 따라서 언어 대 언어 또는 텍스트 대 텍스트 작업에서는
this is really adding in grammatical or sequential context to the representation itself as it flows
이는 실제로 표현 자체가 흐름에 따라 문법적 또는 순차적 맥락을 추가하는 것입니다.
through the model, and it's all about extracting features that have this superimposed context
모델을 통해 중첩된 컨텍스트가 있는 특징을 추출하는 것이 전부입니다.
that's insanely powerful to allow the decoder to then get different perspectives into the data,
디코더가 데이터에 대해 다양한 관점을 얻을 수 있도록 하는 것은 엄청나게 강력합니다.
so that for every token it can grab the context that is most important for it.
그래서 모든 토큰에 대해 가장 중요한 컨텍스트를 파악할 수 있습니다.
The decoder, on the other hand, is going to have a similar process, but it's going to mask
반면에 디코더는 비슷한 프로세스를 거치게 되지만 마스크를 사용하게 됩니다.
the self-attention so that we don't have that forward-looking bias, and it's going to have an
우리가 미래 지향적 편견을 가지지 않도록 자기 관심을 기울이는 것입니다.
additional cross-attention into the encoder to grab that information that's useful from before.
이전에 유용한 정보를 얻기 위해 인코더에 추가 교차 주의를 기울입니다.
Now in both these situations, as we get further into the implementation, I'll talk about it,
이제 이 두 가지 상황 모두에서 구현에 대해 더 자세히 설명하겠습니다.
but we have a final feedforward network that's added into these blocks, and what this feedforward
하지만 우리는 이 블록에 추가된 최종 피드포워드 네트워크를 가지고 있으며, 이 피드포워드는 무엇을 의미합니까?
network is going to do is if the multi-head attention is adding context about what's important,
네트워크가 할 일은 다중 헤드 주의가 중요한 것에 대한 컨텍스트를 추가하는 것입니다.
the feedforward network is going to allow us to exploit that context
피드포워드 네트워크를 통해 우리는 해당 컨텍스트를 활용할 수 있습니다.
so that we can get a richer representation going forwards. So the multi-head attention says these
앞으로 더 풍부한 표현을 얻을 수 있도록 말이죠. 따라서 다중 헤드 주의는 다음과 같이 말합니다.
things are the things you should be paying attention to, and the feedforward network at any
주의해야 할 사항은 피드포워드 네트워크입니다.
single situation is going to say, okay, based on this attention, this is what I want to be doing
단일 상황에서는 '좋아, 이 관심을 바탕으로 이것이 내가 하고 싶은 일'이라고 말할 것입니다.
with my signal. Between all of these kind of sub-layers or sub-attention blocks, we have
내 신호로. 이러한 모든 종류의 하위 계층 또는 하위 주의 블록 사이에는
these connections, so these sub-layer connections, and I'll talk more about those in the future,
이러한 연결, 이러한 하위 계층 연결에 대해서는 나중에 더 자세히 설명하겠습니다.
but they're really there to regularize the signal and make sure that we don't have any problems with
하지만 실제로는 신호를 정규화하고 문제가 없는지 확인하기 위해 존재합니다.
exploding or vanishing gradients or we don't overfit the data that we've seen.
그라디언트가 폭발하거나 사라지거나 우리가 본 데이터에 과적합되지 않습니다.
The generator is a final head that's attached to the architecture, and it's very simple. It's
생성기는 아키텍처에 부착되는 최종 헤드이며 매우 간단합니다. 그것은
going to take a linear layer, flow into a softmax, and that's going to produce based on the
선형 레이어를 가져와서 소프트맥스로 흐르게 하고, 이는 다음을 기반으로 생성됩니다.
logits that the model produced. It's going to take that and transform them into output probabilities
모델이 생산한 로짓. 이를 취하여 출력 확률로 변환합니다.
in the vocabulary that you're training. Now as far as the decoding process goes,
당신이 훈련하고 있는 어휘에서. 이제 디코딩 프로세스가 진행되는 한,
this is typically done greedily, so you just do kind of like an argmax. You take the most likely
이것은 일반적으로 탐욕스럽게 수행되므로 일종의 argmax와 같은 작업을 수행합니다. 당신은 가장 가능성이 높은 것을 선택합니다
probability and just decode that directly as the next token. When you're training the model,
확률을 확인하고 이를 다음 토큰으로 직접 디코딩하면 됩니다. 모델을 훈련할 때,
we don't really deal with the decoded tokens. We always keep it in an encoded state. That way,
우리는 실제로 디코딩된 토큰을 다루지 않습니다. 우리는 항상 인코딩된 상태로 유지합니다. 그런 식으로,
we can just continue to flow through the training process. As Aveline mentioned earlier, Veswanian
우리는 훈련 과정을 계속해서 진행할 수 있습니다. Aveline이 앞서 언급했듯이 Veswanian은
is colleagues use a fixed dimensional implementation. They use D model throughout the architecture,
동료들은 고정 차원 구현을 사용합니다. 그들은 아키텍처 전반에 걸쳐 D 모델을 사용합니다.
at least as far as what's handed between layers. The reason for this is it's going to make it very
적어도 레이어 사이에 전달되는 것까지. 그 이유는 그것이 매우 성공할 것이기 때문이다.
easy to stack these blocks, so the encoder blocks and the decoder blocks, to achieve depth in our
이러한 블록을 쉽게 쌓을 수 있으므로 인코더 블록과 디코더 블록을 통해 깊이를 얻을 수 있습니다.
model. The more parameters, the better the neural network is going to be at approximating whatever
모델. 매개변수가 많을수록 신경망은 무엇이든 더 잘 근사할 수 있습니다.
the task you're doing is. Now I want to clear up real quick while I've got this diagram on screen,
당신이 하고 있는 일은. 이제 이 다이어그램이 화면에 표시되는 동안 빨리 정리하고 싶습니다.
the notion of stacking transformer blocks, and I'll do this a little bit further when I clear
변압기 블록을 쌓는 개념에 대해 알아보겠습니다.
up another misconception later on, but where you see this times n, this is referring to that actual
나중에 또 다른 오해가 생기겠지만, 여기서 n 번을 보는 것은 실제
block itself. So when we stack encoder blocks, it's going to be an encoder on top of another
자체를 차단합니다. 따라서 인코더 블록을 쌓으면 다른 블록 위에 인코더가 됩니다.
encoder and a decoder on top of another decoder. The paper that the authors produced themselves
다른 디코더 위에 인코더와 디코더가 있습니다. 저자가 직접 제작한 논문
used six stacked encoder blocks and stacked decoder blocks, but as far as this figure goes,
6개의 스택된 인코더 블록과 스택된 디코더 블록을 사용했지만 이 그림에 따르면
I think it can be a little bit misleading about what the times n means here, and you want to
제 생각에는 n번이 여기서 의미하는 바에 대해 약간 오해의 소지가 있을 수 있다고 생각합니다.
think of it as stacking the encoders and the decoders, not stacking full transformers.
전체 변압기를 쌓는 것이 아니라 인코더와 디코더를 쌓는 것으로 생각하십시오.
Okay, so with that out of the way, I want to go into a little bit of the
좋아요, 그럼 그건 제쳐두고 좀 더 자세히 들어가 보겠습니다.
implementational details, and I'm going to be leveraging the annotated transformer,
구현 세부 사항을 설명하고 주석이 달린 변환기를 활용하겠습니다.
which is an excellent resource, I put the link down below on the slide, to go through this
이는 훌륭한 리소스이므로 이 내용을 살펴보기 위해 아래 슬라이드에 링크를 걸어 두었습니다.
as part of my explanation, and I encourage you to actually go and read this yourself.
내 설명의 일부로, 실제로 가서 직접 읽어 보시기 바랍니다.
You'll have more time to look at the code and reflect on what that means with
코드를 살펴보고 이것이 무엇을 의미하는지 생각해 볼 시간이 더 있을 것입니다.
relationship to the actual paper, which they include snippets of and essentially just walk
실제 논문과의 관계. 여기에는 일부 내용이 포함되어 있으며 기본적으로는 그냥 걸어다닙니다.
through what the paper means step by step. So it's a great resource. For the presentation today,
종이가 의미하는 바를 단계별로 설명합니다. 그래서 훌륭한 자원입니다. 오늘 발표를 위해,
I want to treat building the transformer kind of like building a Lego house. We're going to start
저는 트랜스포머를 조립하는 것을 마치 레고 하우스를 짓는 것처럼 다루고 싶습니다. 우리는 시작할거야
really small with little blocks and then build up different modules that we can then compose
작은 블록으로 정말 작은 다음 구성할 수 있는 다양한 모듈을 구축합니다.
together and build out the final transformer architecture that you might use or implement in
함께 사용하거나 구현할 수 있는 최종 변환기 아키텍처를 구축합니다.
real life. And I'm going to present it in a slightly different order than what the annotated
실생활. 그리고 나는 주석이 달린 순서와 약간 다른 순서로 그것을 제시할 것입니다.
transformer does, because I think it fits the narrative that we're trying to display to you
트랜스포머는 그렇습니다. 우리가 여러분에게 보여주고자 하는 이야기에 적합하다고 생각하기 때문입니다.
a little bit better. So if I was to go about building the Lego house that is this transformer,
조금 더 나은. 그래서 제가 이 트랜스포머인 레고 하우스를 짓는다면,
when we want to talk about this, it might be helpful so that you don't have a lot of repeated
우리가 이것에 대해 이야기하고 싶을 때, 반복해서 많이 하지 않도록 도움이 될 수 있습니다.
code to introduce some type of cloning or copying function. So if we design a subcomponent,
일종의 복제 또는 복사 기능을 도입하는 코드입니다. 따라서 하위 구성요소를 설계하면
say it's a wall of this hypothetical house, I want to be able to make a whole bunch of walls that
이것이 이 가상의 집의 벽이라고 가정해 보겠습니다. 저는 그런 벽을 잔뜩 만들 수 있기를 원합니다.
look the same so that I can then use that to build the infrastructure or in this situation,
인프라를 구축하는 데 사용할 수 있도록 동일하게 보이거나 이 상황에서
the architecture of the transformer. So the main motivation here is if we can repeat elements,
변압기의 아키텍처. 여기서 주된 동기는 요소를 반복할 수 있는지,
we can then stack them deeper with no real design cost behind it. And like the VGG implementation,
그런 다음 실제 설계 비용 없이 더 깊게 쌓을 수 있습니다. VGG 구현과 마찬가지로
which was a computer vision implementation, not necessarily related to this, but they
이는 컴퓨터 비전 구현이었으며 꼭 이와 관련이 있는 것은 아니지만
added this idea of having composable blocks that you can stack. So we want to be doing that with
쌓을 수 있는 구성 가능한 블록이 있다는 아이디어를 추가했습니다. 그래서 우리는 그 일을 하고 싶습니다
our transformers as well. So this function is going to be called clones. And essentially what
우리 트랜스포머도 마찬가지야. 그래서 이 기능을 클론이라고 부르겠습니다. 그리고 본질적으로 무엇
it's going to do is given a module, in this case, we're doing this in PyTorch, create n copies of
할 일은 모듈을 제공하는 것입니다. 이 경우에는 PyTorch에서 이 작업을 수행하고 n 개의 복사본을 만듭니다.
it. Now whenever you're creating clones of something that has learned parameters in either PyTorch or
그것. 이제 PyTorch 또는 PyTorch에서 매개변수를 학습한 무언가의 복제본을 생성할 때마다
TensorFlow, it's important that these, unless explicitly designed that way, these clones should
TensorFlow에서는 명시적으로 그렇게 설계하지 않는 한 이러한 클론이
not share the same parameters. And with the transformer, we want to make sure they're separate
동일한 매개변수를 공유하지 마십시오. 그리고 변압기를 사용하여 우리는 그것들이 분리되어 있는지 확인하고 싶습니다.
so that the different heads learn separate things, or that the different stacks learn,
서로 다른 헤드가 별개의 것을 배우거나, 서로 다른 스택이 학습하도록
or different stacked blocks of the encoder or decoder are learning separate parameters,
또는 인코더 또는 디코더의 서로 다른 스택 블록이 별도의 매개변수를 학습하고 있습니다.
that way they have the full power of being able to optimize to that specific part of the network.
그렇게 하면 그들은 네트워크의 특정 부분을 최적화할 수 있는 모든 능력을 갖게 됩니다.
So when we actually go to make this model, you need to remember the very end to
그래서 우리가 실제로 이 모델을 만들러 갈 때, 여러분은 이 모델의 마지막 부분을 기억해야 합니다.
reinitialize all of the model parameters so that they're separate and independent per clone.
모든 모델 매개변수를 다시 초기화하여 클론별로 분리되고 독립적이 되도록 합니다.
Okay, so with that understood, let's build the first part of our architecture, our Lego house.
좋아요, 이해한 바에 따라 건축물의 첫 번째 부분인 레고 하우스를 만들어 봅시다.
And in this situation, we need to understand how we're going to get information
그리고 이런 상황에서 우리는 어떻게 정보를 얻을 수 있는지 이해해야 합니다.
into our transformer in the first place. So I mentioned earlier that we're going to use
우선 우리 변압기에 들어가세요. 그래서 앞서 우리가 사용할 것이라고 언급한 바 있습니다.
embeddings into kind of a numerical system of the input vocabulary. Now if these are tokens,
입력 어휘의 일종의 수치 시스템에 임베딩합니다. 이제 이것이 토큰이라면,
such as those associated with words, we essentially need to be able to take
단어와 관련된 것과 같이 우리는 본질적으로
the independent parts or the individual parts of say a phrase like I am James,
I am James와 같은 문구의 독립적인 부분이나 개별적인 부분,
and break that up into little sub pieces that can then be turned into numerical
그리고 이를 숫자로 변환할 수 있는 작은 하위 조각으로 나눕니다.
vectors of fixed length that we can then feed into the model. And this is mainly because neural
고정 길이의 벡터를 모델에 입력할 수 있습니다. 그리고 이것은 주로 신경 때문입니다.
architectures, they work on numbers. Additionally, when you're dealing with a large possible vocabulary,
아키텍처는 숫자에 대해 작업합니다. 게다가, 가능한 많은 어휘를 다룰 때,
like the entirety of the English language, or in modern large language models, maybe the entire
영어 전체나 현대의 대규모 언어 모델처럼 어쩌면 전체
vocabulary of all languages, we have a large number of words or symbols that represent or
모든 언어의 어휘에는 다음을 나타내는 수많은 단어나 기호가 있습니다.
communicate meaning for that sequence. And we don't want our neural network to be
해당 시퀀스의 의미를 전달합니다. 그리고 우리는 신경망이 다음과 같이 되는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
extremely wide as far as the dimension goes, because it's going to be inefficient and take
차원이 가는 한 매우 넓습니다. 왜냐하면 비효율적이고 시간이 많이 걸리기 때문입니다.
a long, long time to calculate each layer. So as part of this embedding process, a benefit
각 레이어를 계산하는 데 오랜 시간이 걸립니다. 따라서 이러한 임베딩 프로세스의 일부로 다음과 같은 이점이 있습니다.
of converting to this numerical system is we're going to reduce the dimensionality
이 수치 시스템으로 변환하면 차원이 줄어들 것입니다.
and make computation more efficient. Now how we go about kind of building these embeddings
그리고 계산을 더 효율적으로 만듭니다. 이제 이러한 임베딩을 구축하는 방법은 무엇입니까?
is using a learned mapping. You can think of this like a standard linear projection that you'd have
학습된 매핑을 사용하고 있습니다. 이것을 표준 선형 투영처럼 생각할 수 있습니다.
in a neural network, except instead of doing like a linear layer, we're going to have a dictionary
신경망에서는 선형 레이어처럼 수행하는 대신 사전을 갖게 됩니다.
that's going to look up or map to the vocabulary and have corresponding unique vectors. So we
이는 어휘를 조회하거나 매핑하고 해당 고유 벡터를 갖게 됩니다. 그래서 우리는
essentially learn weights that are going to go and do that look up to find out what the
본질적으로 앞으로 나아갈 가중치를 배우고 그 결과가 무엇인지 알아보기 위해 검색을 수행합니다.
corresponding word is. But it's still doing this linear layer. Once you've got it into the numerical
해당 단어는 입니다. 하지만 여전히 선형 레이어를 수행하고 있습니다. 일단 숫자로 입력하면
space, we still do a linear layer to get it to that final embedding.
공간이 있는 경우 최종 임베딩에 도달하기 위해 여전히 선형 레이어를 사용합니다.
Now the next element of how we're going to get data into our transformer is the positional
이제 변환기로 데이터를 가져오는 방법의 다음 요소는 위치입니다.
encoding. And what this is doing is it's going to add information about the element in the
부호화. 그리고 이것이 하는 일은 요소에 대한 정보를 추가하는 것입니다.
sequences position with reference to the other elements. And we do this explicitly so that
다른 요소를 참조하여 시퀀스 위치를 지정합니다. 그리고 우리는 이것을 명시적으로 수행합니다.
we can avoid the recurrence or convolutional structure, because when you're doing computation,
반복이나 컨벌루션 구조를 피할 수 있습니다. 왜냐하면 계산을 할 때
the representation itself has that information kind of layered on top of it or interweaved
표현 자체에는 그 위에 계층화되거나 얽혀 있는 정보가 있습니다.
with that signal. And how we can go about doing this is because we've produced a fixed dimensional
그 신호로. 그리고 우리가 이것을 할 수 있는 방법은 우리가 고정된 차원을 만들어냈기 때문입니다.
embedded representation of the feature for the input sequence, since it's fixed dimensional,
입력 시퀀스에 대한 기능의 내장된 표현(고정 차원이므로)
we can actually do an element wise addition to add in that positional element or information.
실제로 위치 요소나 정보를 추가하기 위해 요소별 추가를 수행할 수 있습니다.
As long as that positional information shares the same dimension with the embedded feature.
해당 위치 정보가 포함된 기능과 동일한 차원을 공유하는 한.
So the authors go about this in a couple of ways. The one that they highlight in their paper is that
그래서 저자들은 이에 대해 몇 가지 방법을 사용합니다. 그들이 논문에서 강조한 점은
they utilize the sinusoidal positional encoding. And they do this in favor of other approaches
정현파 위치 인코딩을 활용합니다. 그리고 그들은 다른 접근법을 선호하여 이렇게 합니다.
like a learned positional encoding using an MLP that they also experimented with,
실험한 MLP를 사용하여 학습된 위치 인코딩과 같이
because the sinusoidal representation is number one, a little bit more intuitive
정현파 표현이 1위이기 때문에 조금 더 직관적입니다.
to understand. And number two, because sine waves have that repeating fashion and you can represent
이해하다. 두 번째, 사인파는 반복되는 방식을 갖고 있으며 이를 표현할 수 있기 때문입니다.
an offset from one position to another position as a linear function, they hypothesize that as
선형 함수로서 한 위치에서 다른 위치로의 오프셋을 가정하면 다음과 같습니다.
context lengths get longer and longer, it'll allow the model to easily learn how to attend to
컨텍스트 길이가 점점 길어지면 모델이 컨텍스트에 주의를 기울이는 방법을 쉽게 배울 수 있습니다.
relevant positions between different elements and possibly generalize to longer sequence lengths
서로 다른 요소 간의 관련 위치 및 더 긴 시퀀스 길이로 일반화 가능
than they were trained on, a little bit better. So as far as this goes, what they do is essentially
훈련받은 것보다 조금 더 나아졌습니다. 따라서 이 문제에 관한 한 그들이 하는 일은 본질적으로 다음과 같습니다.
interweave the cosine signal and a sine signal. I've got the equations for these off to the side
코사인 신호와 사인 신호를 엮습니다. 나는 이것에 대한 방정식을 옆에 가지고 있습니다.
where I is going to represent the position in the sequence and L is going to be the
여기서 나는 시퀀스의 위치를 ​​나타내고 L은
index into the dimension of the representation for that given element in the sequence.
시퀀스의 해당 요소에 대한 표현의 차원에 대한 색인입니다.
So the signal gets embedded into that representation of the element based on the index L,
따라서 신호는 인덱스 L을 기반으로 한 요소 표현에 포함됩니다.
and then for each token in the sequence or each element in this arbitrary sequence,
그런 다음 시퀀스의 각 토큰 또는 이 임의 시퀀스의 각 요소에 대해
we're going to be adding in that positional information based on where it is or its index I.
우리는 그것이 어디에 있는지 또는 인덱스 I를 기반으로 위치 정보를 추가할 것입니다.
There are further works that have built on top of the transformer to kind of improve how we're
우리가 사용하는 방식을 개선하기 위해 변압기 위에 구축된 추가 작업이 있습니다.
getting this positional encoding. Rope is a great method that was produced after the fact
이 위치 인코딩을 얻는 중입니다. 로프는 사후에 만들어진 훌륭한 방법이다.
and is highly used nowadays. I encourage you to kind of go and look at that up. If you're
요즘에는 많이 사용됩니다. 나는 당신이 가서 그것을 살펴 보는 것이 좋습니다. 만약 당신이
going to implement this yourself, it's important to understand where the foundation is, so what
이를 직접 구현하려면 기초가 어디에 있는지 이해하는 것이 중요합니다.
the original transformer paper used, and it's easy to wrap your head around what's happening,
원래의 변압기 종이가 사용되었으며 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 머리를 감싸는 것이 쉽습니다.
where we're adding or embedding this positional encoding. But if you use a rotary positional
여기서 이 위치 인코딩을 추가하거나 삽입합니다. 그러나 회전식 위치 지정을 사용하는 경우
encoding, which is more of a modern feature, you can get the same level of expressiveness,
좀 더 현대적인 기능인 인코딩을 사용하면 동일한 수준의 표현력을 얻을 수 있습니다.
but without needing two separate signals. So it's something I encourage you to go and look at after.
하지만 두 개의 별도 신호가 필요하지 않습니다. 그래서 저는 여러분이 가서 살펴보시기를 권하는 것입니다.
Nonetheless, the main idea is as far as implementation goes, we're going to have
그럼에도 불구하고, 주요 아이디어는 구현이 진행되는 한, 우리는
some function that's going to add in that positional information to the actual
실제 위치 정보에 추가할 함수
feature representation that the model is going to take, so the information is going to be there.
모델이 취할 특징 표현이므로 정보가 거기에 있을 것입니다.
And if we look at our high torch code off to the side, you can see I've highlighted the element
그리고 옆에 있는 하이 토치 코드를 보면 요소가 강조 표시된 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
where we're computing the sine wave and the cost wave for each element, and then we just interleave
각 요소에 대한 사인파와 비용파를 계산한 다음 인터리브합니다.
them together and then do our linear projection. So we're not linear projection, we're doing the
그것들을 함께 사용한 다음 선형 투영을 수행합니다. 따라서 우리는 선형 투영이 아니라 다음을 수행하고 있습니다.
in-place addition of that signal with the actual feature representation.
실제 기능 표현과 함께 해당 신호를 제자리에 추가합니다.
So with that understood, we've talked about how we're going to get information
이를 이해한 상태에서 정보를 얻는 방법에 대해 이야기했습니다.
into our model, and you keep in mind that this happens in the encoder, but also with the previously
이 문제는 인코더에서 발생하지만 이전 모델에서도 발생한다는 점을 기억하세요.
decoded token. So we also go through that embedding and positional encoding to get ready to go into
디코딩된 토큰. 따라서 우리는 임베딩 및 위치 인코딩을 통해 다음 단계로 들어갈 준비를 합니다.
the decoder layer. But once we've got information that's ready to be taken by this encoder-decoder
디코더 레이어. 하지만 일단 이 인코더-디코더가 가져올 수 있는 정보를 얻었으면
structure, we need to talk about what the encoder-decoder structure actually looks like.
구조에 관해서는 인코더-디코더 구조가 실제로 어떻게 보이는지에 대해 이야기해야 합니다.
So both the encoder and the decoder have a number of sub-layers that are going to be
따라서 인코더와 디코더 모두에는 다음과 같은 여러 하위 계층이 있습니다.
useful for building out their structure, one of which is the multi-head attention sub-layer,
구조를 구축하는 데 유용하며 그 중 하나는 다중 헤드 주의 하위 계층입니다.
and this is going to carry out that multi-head attention, learning the weights that allow us
그리고 이것은 다중 헤드 주의를 수행하여 우리에게 허용되는 가중치를 학습할 것입니다.
to create keys, values, and queries like we talked about earlier. And the main idea behind this,
앞서 이야기한 것처럼 키, 값, 쿼리를 생성합니다. 그리고 이것의 주요 아이디어는,
like we've talked about earlier, is to extract the relevant context from an input sequence
앞서 이야기한 것처럼 입력 시퀀스에서 관련 컨텍스트를 추출하는 것입니다.
and we leverage multiple heads to provide a greater resolution or different views
여러 헤드를 활용하여 더 높은 해상도나 다양한 뷰를 제공합니다.
into the problem so that that context is available from different angles. And how this is implemented
해당 컨텍스트를 다양한 각도에서 사용할 수 있도록 문제에 접근합니다. 그리고 이것이 어떻게 구현되는지
is directly how we explained it earlier. If you want to look at a code representation of this,
우리가 이전에 설명했던 바로 그 방법입니다. 이에 대한 코드 표현을 보려면
we're still using that scaled dot product implementation. So if we're doing just the
우리는 여전히 확장된 내적 구현을 ​​사용하고 있습니다. 그래서 우리가 단지
attention here, and keep in mind that these are the keys, values, and queries after doing that
여기에 주의를 기울이고 이를 수행한 후의 키, 값 및 쿼리라는 점을 명심하세요.
linear projection, right? So this is just the attention function itself. We do our matrix
선형 투영이죠? 그래서 이것은 단지 어텐션 함수 그 자체입니다. 우리는 매트릭스를 수행합니다
multiplication of our query and our keys, scale it by the dimension dk, and then if you see at
쿼리와 키를 곱하고 dk 차원으로 크기를 조정한 다음 다음과 같이 표시됩니다.
the very bottom here, we're then going to take the attention weights after normalizing through
여기 맨 아래에서 정규화한 후 주의 가중치를 취하겠습니다.
softmax and multiply them by the values to extract how much of each value we're using or
소프트맥스에 값을 곱하여 우리가 사용하는 각 값의 양을 추출하거나
how much we need to attend to that. Now, there are a couple of useful things that you can build
우리가 그것에 얼마나 주의를 기울여야 하는지. 이제 여러분이 만들 수 있는 몇 가지 유용한 것들이 있습니다.
into your implementation when you're doing it. One is this idea of masking and the other is dropout.
당신이 그것을 할 때 당신의 구현에. 하나는 마스킹 아이디어이고 다른 하나는 드롭아웃입니다.
The main idea for incorporating these when you're designing your own implementation is it's going
자신만의 구현을 설계할 때 이러한 기능을 통합하는 주요 아이디어는 다음과 같습니다.
to speed up the ability to compose these models because you don't need to design a custom attention
사용자 정의 관심을 디자인할 필요가 없기 때문에 이러한 모델을 구성하는 능력을 가속화합니다.
function for the encoder or a custom one for the decoder because we know the decoder is going to
인코더에 대한 함수 또는 디코더에 대한 사용자 지정 함수
be using this masking. We can set it as a parameter of this function so that you can use the exact
이 마스킹을 사용하세요. 정확한 정보를 사용할 수 있도록 이 함수의 매개변수로 설정할 수 있습니다.
same attention function for both the encoder and decoder. The dropout here is just a benefit of
인코더와 디코더 모두에 동일한 주의 기능이 있습니다. 여기서의 드롭아웃은 단지 이점일 뿐입니다.
our sublayer connections and in general just a regularization strategy that we're going to use
하위 계층 연결과 일반적으로 우리가 사용할 정규화 전략
throughout the model. Dropout just essentially drops the some random features inside of our
모델 전반에 걸쳐. Dropout은 기본적으로 우리 내부의 일부 임의 기능을 삭제합니다.
representation so that our model doesn't tend to overfit to the data that it's seeing. So this is
모델이 보고 있는 데이터에 과적합되는 경향이 없도록 표현합니다. 그래서 이것은
a form of implicit regularization that's a useful pattern to build into networks as you get deeper
더 깊이 들어가면서 네트워크에 구축하는 데 유용한 패턴인 암시적 정규화의 한 형태입니다.
and deeper to avoid overfitting. Now, building on this attention function is the idea of the
과적합을 피하기 위해 더 깊게 만듭니다. 이제 이 주의 기능을 기반으로 하는 아이디어는 다음과 같습니다.
multi-head attention. Now, again, there's this ambiguity about what the multi-head attention's
다중 주의. 자, 다시 말하지만, 다중 헤드 어텐션이 무엇인지에 대한 모호함이 있습니다.
notation is. When we look at the forward pass here where we're taking a query, a key, and a value,
표기법은. 여기서 쿼리, 키, 값을 취하는 정방향 전달을 살펴보면,
I would name these something different, but the common implementations that are corresponding
나는 이것을 다른 이름으로 지정하고 싶지만 이에 상응하는 일반적인 구현은
with the paper are going to name them the query, key, and value. Think of these as the actual
종이에 쿼리, 키, 값의 이름을 지정합니다. 이것들을 실제라고 생각하세요
signals themselves before they go through that linear projection that's going to take them to
선형 투영을 통과하기 전에 스스로에게 신호를 보냅니다.
that other space, the subrepresentation that is being learned. So in this situation,
그 다른 공간, 학습되고 있는 하위표상. 그래서 이 상황에서,
if we were doing self-attention, the query, key, and value would all be the same thing.
self-attention을 수행한다면 쿼리, 키, 값은 모두 동일할 것입니다.
And when we're doing a cross-attention implementation, the query would be from one
교차 어텐션 구현을 수행할 때 쿼리는 다음 중 하나에서 발생합니다.
source, the decoded sequence that we're decoding, and the key and value would come from a memory
소스, 우리가 디코딩하고 있는 디코딩된 시퀀스, 키와 값은 메모리에서 나옵니다.
of what the encoded source looks like. Either way, I've highlighted the relevant parts here.
인코딩된 소스의 모습. 어느 쪽이든 여기서는 관련 부분을 강조했습니다.
Namely, we're going to go through, and because we've got this matrix multiplication and we want
즉, 우리는 이 행렬 곱셈을 얻었고 우리가 원하는 것은 다음과 같습니다.
to accelerate this on modern hardware, we can build in this notion of batching to really take
최신 하드웨어에서 이를 가속화하기 위해 일괄 처리 개념을 구축하여 실제로
advantage of the self-attention and make it concurrent and fast. So if we do all of our
self-attention을 활용하여 동시적이고 빠르게 수행합니다. 그러니 우리가 우리의 모든 일을 한다면
linear projections at once, and that's what you see in this block with the comment that
선형 투영을 한 번에 수행할 수 있으며 이것이 바로 이 블록에서 다음과 같은 주석과 함께 볼 수 있는 것입니다.
starts with the number one, we're going to go through, carry out all of these projections,
첫 번째부터 시작해서 우리는 이 모든 예측을 진행하고 수행할 것입니다.
and it's going to let us get to the point where we can feed it into our attention mechanism,
그리고 이를 우리의 주의 메커니즘에 적용할 수 있는 지점에 도달하게 될 것입니다.
which follows right beneath it very quickly and in parallel. We then go through the process of
그 바로 아래에서 매우 빠르고 평행하게 따라옵니다. 그런 다음 우리는 다음과 같은 과정을 거칩니다.
concatenating all of the different multiple attention heads, and then finally at the very
다양한 다중 어텐션 헤드를 모두 연결한 다음 마지막으로
bottom we do a linear projection using that learned weights matrix to take us back to the
하단에서 학습된 가중치 행렬을 사용하여 선형 투영을 수행하여 다음으로 돌아갑니다.
dimension of the model that we can feed into the rest of it. So this is really just taking us
나머지 부분에 입력할 수 있는 모델의 차원입니다. 그래서 이것은 정말로 우리를 데려가는 것입니다
through that multi-head attention process that I explained earlier, but giving a little bit
앞서 설명했던 다중 머리 주의 과정을 통해
of an implementation detail here. You can see on the left hand side where we're initializing
구현 세부 사항은 여기에서 확인하세요. 초기화 중인 위치를 왼쪽에서 볼 수 있습니다.
the multi-head attention block for sublayer, that we are cloning the actual layers that are
하위 레이어에 대한 다중 헤드 어텐션 블록은 실제 레이어를 복제하고 있음을 의미합니다.
going to be used to learn the matrix sees, or the parameters of the model. That way we can
매트릭스 보기 또는 모델의 매개변수를 학습하는 데 사용됩니다. 그렇게 하면 우리는 할 수 있다
essentially, instead of needing to copy each one as a code block, we just copy the module itself
기본적으로 각 항목을 코드 블록으로 복사할 필요 없이 모듈 자체만 복사하면 됩니다.
to build out the eight attention heads that this model is going to expect, keeping in mind that
이 모델이 기대하는 8개의 주목 헤드를 구축하려면 다음을 명심하세요.
we need to reinitialize all those values so that they're independent of one another before we
우리는 모든 값이 서로 독립적이도록 다시 초기화해야 합니다.
start training. Okay, so with the first sublayer understood, I'm going to move into the second
훈련을 시작합니다. 좋아요, 첫 번째 하위 레이어를 이해했으니 두 번째 하위 레이어로 넘어가겠습니다.
one, which is the position-wise feedforward network. And what's happening here, or an intuition
하나는 위치별 피드포워드 네트워크입니다. 그리고 여기서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지, 아니면 직관이
for it, is that it's going to apply a learned transformation to each position in the input
그 이유는 학습된 변환을 입력의 각 위치에 적용한다는 것입니다.
representation, but they're applied separately and identically. So when we go through the
표현하지만 별도로 동일하게 적용됩니다. 그래서 우리가 그 과정을 겪을 때
multi-head attention, we're essentially going to convert our values dimension into our queries
Multi-head attention, 우리는 본질적으로 가치 차원을 쿼리로 변환할 것입니다.
dimension, right? So we sum through the values per query. What we want to do with the position-wide
차원이죠? 따라서 쿼리당 값을 합산합니다. 우리가 포지션 전체로 하고 싶은 것
feedforward network is we've added in that context per query. We now want to per query, so keep that
피드포워드 네트워크는 쿼리별로 해당 컨텍스트에 추가했습니다. 이제 쿼리별로 실행하고 싶으므로 이를 유지하세요.
independence of each query lane, but now exploit that context. So we're going to blow it up,
각 쿼리 레인의 독립성을 유지하지만 이제는 해당 컨텍스트를 활용합니다. 그래서 우리는 그것을 폭파시킬 것입니다.
learn how to map it to something more useful, and then recompress it in dimension. So we want to
좀 더 유용한 것으로 매핑한 다음 차원에서 다시 압축하는 방법을 알아보세요. 그래서 우리는
exploit the context that's already been added by previous sublayers. And the main idea is that
이전 하위 계층에 의해 이미 추가된 컨텍스트를 활용합니다. 그리고 주요 아이디어는
we're adding more parameters to the network so that it can approximate a greater complexity.
우리는 더 큰 복잡성을 근사화할 수 있도록 네트워크에 더 많은 매개변수를 추가하고 있습니다.
And at the end of the day, a neural network is a universal approximator as you get
그리고 결국 신경망은 보편적인 근사치입니다.
deeper or wider arbitrarily. And the main idea is we want to learn how to go from one sequence to
임의로 더 깊거나 더 넓어집니다. 그리고 주요 아이디어는 우리가 하나의 시퀀스에서 다음 시퀀스로 이동하는 방법을 배우고 싶다는 것입니다.
another sequence with the task of sequencing a sequence translation. So the more parameters,
시퀀스 번역을 시퀀싱하는 작업이 포함된 또 다른 시퀀스입니다. 따라서 매개변수가 많을수록
the better your model will be, assuming it's been trained well. And then the main idea here,
모델이 잘 훈련되었다고 가정하면 모델이 더 좋아질 것입니다. 그리고 여기의 주요 아이디어는,
or how it's going about exploiting this context, is it's going to increase the resolution of
또는 이 컨텍스트를 어떻게 활용할 것인지, 해상도를 높일 것인가?
each position momentarily to allow the model to simulate something that's got,
모델이 가지고 있는 것을 시뮬레이션할 수 있도록 각 위치를 순간적으로
or to exploit this superposition of context. So unravel it a little bit,
또는 이러한 맥락의 중첩을 활용합니다. 그럼 조금 풀어서,
do some computation, and then remap back to that fixed dimension of the model. So they do this
몇 가지 계산을 수행한 다음 모델의 고정된 차원으로 다시 매핑합니다. 그래서 그들은 이렇게 해요
through a linear MLP or a fully connected feedforward network with ReLU activations in between.
선형 MLP 또는 ReLU 활성화가 있는 완전히 연결된 피드포워드 네트워크를 통해.
And the keynote is that the hidden space is going to have higher dimensionality.
그리고 핵심은 숨겨진 공간이 더 높은 차원성을 갖게 될 것이라는 점입니다.
So I've drawn a picture off to the side just to explain this a little bit. When you've got the
그래서 이것을 조금 설명하기 위해 옆에 그림을 그렸습니다. 당신이 가지고있을 때
superposition of contexts, you might see that the positional nodes have different elements
컨텍스트가 중첩되면 위치 노드에 다른 요소가 있음을 알 수 있습니다.
that are adding to the context. Now, because as you go deeper in neural networks, we kind of lose
맥락에 추가되는 것입니다. 이제 신경망에 대해 더 깊이 들어갈수록 우리는
that discernible meaning, the meaning's still there, but there's a lot of contesies that are
그 식별 가능한 의미는 여전히 존재하지만 논쟁의 여지가 많이 있습니다.
wrapped up into a single node's representation. So it's hard to isolate that. So I've just come
단일 노드 표현으로 요약됩니다. 그래서 그것을 분리하는 것이 어렵습니다. 그래서 방금 왔어
up with like some colors that I've assigned. You could think maybe one of them is about what the
내가 지정한 색상과 비슷해졌습니다. 아마도 그 중 하나가 무엇에 관한 것인지 생각할 수 있습니다.
actual words meaning was in an encoded sequence. Some of it is the relation to another element,
실제 단어 의미는 인코딩된 순서로 되어 있었습니다. 그 중 일부는 다른 요소와의 관계입니다.
maybe the purple is relation to another element in the sequence, or one of its neighbors.
보라색은 시퀀스의 다른 요소나 그 이웃 요소 중 하나와 관련이 있을 수 있습니다.
But the main idea is during this feedforward, or the position-wise feedforward sub-layer,
하지만 주요 아이디어는 이 피드포워드 또는 위치별 피드포워드 하위 계층이 진행되는 동안
we're going to blow up the dimension so that different parts of the features can represent
우리는 특징의 다른 부분이 나타낼 수 있도록 차원을 확대할 것입니다.
different things. And then when we go and recombine that, we can recombine it in a different way
다른 것들. 그런 다음 이를 재결합하면 다른 방식으로 재결합할 수 있습니다.
that makes that context more accessible and more useful down the line. As far as the implementation
그러면 해당 컨텍스트에 더 쉽게 접근할 수 있고 더 유용해집니다. 구현까지
goes, the feedforward part of this model is very simple. We're just going to have two linear layers
이 모델의 피드포워드 부분은 매우 간단합니다. 우리는 두 개의 선형 레이어를 갖게 될 것입니다
that are stacked. We're going to add in some dropout to increase the ability to do regularization.
쌓여 있는 것. 우리는 정규화 능력을 높이기 위해 일부 드롭아웃을 추가할 것입니다.
And in a forward pass, we're just going to do one linear projection,
그리고 순방향 패스에서는 선형 투영을 하나만 수행하겠습니다.
do our ReLU on it, then do the next linear projection.
ReLU를 수행하고 다음 선형 투영을 수행합니다.
Perfect. And with that understood, we have the sub-blocks assembled, so these sub-layers.
완벽한. 그리고 이를 이해하면 하위 블록이 조립되므로 이러한 하위 레이어가 있습니다.
But how we go about connecting them is also important. So as far as the implementation goes,
하지만 이를 연결하는 방법도 중요합니다. 구현이 진행되는 한,
I went one slide too far, here we go. So as far as the implementation goes,
한 슬라이드를 너무 멀리 이동했습니다. 이제 시작합니다. 구현이 진행되는 한,
the transformer incorporates a sub-layer connection between these sub-layers,
변압기는 이러한 하위 레이어 사이에 하위 레이어 연결을 통합합니다.
or surrounding each of the sub-layers. And what this is going to do is add in that regularization
또는 각 하위 레이어를 둘러싸는 것입니다. 그리고 이것이 할 일은 정규화를 추가하는 것입니다.
and I guess combat poor gradient behavior throughout the model. So this is just making
모델 전반에 걸쳐 열악한 그라데이션 동작과 싸우는 것 같아요. 그래서 이건 그냥 만드는 거야
it so that we can train stably and we don't overfit to the data. They do this through
안정적으로 훈련할 수 있고 데이터에 과적합되지 않도록 하기 위해서입니다. 그들은 이것을 통해 이것을 한다
three different mechanisms. One is a residual connection. The next is this dropout, which I've
세 가지 다른 메커니즘. 하나는 잔여 연결입니다. 다음은 이 드롭아웃입니다.
already explained, so I've glossed over a little bit. And finally, they use a layer norm as part
이미 설명했기 때문에 조금 얼버무렸습니다. 마지막으로 레이어 표준을 일부로 사용합니다.
of the sub-layer connection. And I've put the formula for what this is down below. So they do a layer
하위 계층 연결의 모습입니다. 그리고 저는 이것이 무엇인지에 대한 공식을 아래에 놓았습니다. 그래서 그들은 레이어를 만듭니다
norm on the original signal, which is what the residual connection is. Essentially, you only
잔여 연결이 무엇인지 원래 신호에 대한 표준입니다. 본질적으로 당신은 단지
pass through in the model to represent a residual element, because it's a lot cheaper to learn a
모델을 통과하여 잔여 요소를 표현하는 방법을 배우는 것이 훨씬 저렴하기 때문입니다.
residual than it is to learn the entire signal, and add the original signal with that learned
잔차는 전체 신호를 학습하고 학습된 신호에 원래 신호를 추가하는 것입니다.
residual. And this preserves more of the original signal through this idea of a skip connection,
잔여. 그리고 이는 건너뛰기 연결이라는 아이디어를 통해 원래 신호를 더 많이 보존합니다.
so where you add x plus the thing you've learned. And it also alleviates some of the issues with
그래서 x에 당신이 배운 것을 추가합니다. 또한 이는 다음과 같은 문제 중 일부를 완화합니다.
vanishing gradient, because we aren't computing as much of a number. So the gradient doesn't have
그래디언트 소실. 왜냐하면 우리는 많은 양의 숫자를 계산하지 않기 때문입니다. 그래서 그라데이션에는 없습니다
the problem of having too large of a number where it becomes poorly behaved. So in general,
숫자가 너무 많아 제대로 동작하지 않는 문제. 그래서 일반적으로,
that's the residual connection. You see that that's wrapped in the layer norm in the situation,
그것이 잔여 연결입니다. 상황에 따라 레이어 표준에 포함되어 있음을 알 수 있습니다.
and what a layer norm is going to do is just scale down the values so that they're well behaved per
레이어 노름이 할 일은 값을 축소하여 각 값이 잘 작동하도록 하는 것입니다.
layer. So based on all of the numbers that are in that single layer, we're going to scale them so
층. 따라서 해당 단일 레이어에 있는 모든 숫자를 기반으로 크기를 조정해 보겠습니다.
that they're well behaved and we don't have vanishing or exploding gradients. As far as
그들은 잘 행동하고 우리는 사라지거나 폭발하는 그라디언트가 없습니다. 한
implementations go, I've put the layer norm off to the side, because I think it's kind of interesting
구현이 진행되면 레이어 표준을 옆으로 치워두었습니다. 왜냐하면 제 생각에는 그것이 좀 흥미롭기 때문입니다.
that this isn't the same as, say, like a, if you're doing a batch norm where you have an
이는 예를 들어 a와 같은 것이 아닙니다. 배치 표준을 수행하는 경우
entire batch, it's not per batch, it's per layer in the situation. So we just essentially calculate
전체 배치, 배치당이 아니라 상황에 따라 레이어당입니다. 그래서 우리는 본질적으로 계산합니다.
the mean and the standard deviation, and then normalize what that layer's activations look like
평균과 표준편차를 구한 다음 해당 레이어의 활성화가 어떻게 보이는지 정규화합니다.
based on that. And then the actual sublayer connection I've put a photo of down and off to
그것을 바탕으로. 그런 다음 실제 하위 레이어 연결에 대한 사진을 올려 놓았습니다.
the right, and this is the more important element. This is how we compose or add in all these
권리이며 이것이 더 중요한 요소입니다. 이것이 우리가 이 모든 것을 구성하거나 추가하는 방법입니다.
different types of regularization to the connections between these sublayers.
이러한 하위 계층 간의 연결에 대한 다양한 유형의 정규화.
You see in the forward pass, we're just going to pass in the dropout on the sublayer,
보시다시피 순방향 패스에서 우리는 하위 레이어의 드롭아웃을 패스할 것입니다.
on the layer normed version of the signal, and the sublayer itself is either that multi-head
신호의 레이어 정규 버전에 있고 하위 레이어 자체는 다중 헤드입니다.
attention or the point position-wise feedforward network. Now, you might notice that this is in
주의 또는 포인트 위치별 피드포워드 네트워크. 이제 이것이
a separate order than what the actual equation is that I put earlier. The equation is derived
제가 앞서 말한 실제 방정식과는 별개의 순서입니다. 방정식이 도출됩니다.
from the paper, and this is one area where the annotated transformers deviates from the source
이는 주석이 달린 변환기가 소스에서 벗어나는 영역 중 하나입니다.
text a little bit, and they find that it's relatively the same, but a little bit cheaper
문자를 조금만 보내면 상대적으로 동일하지만 조금 더 저렴하다는 것을 알게 됩니다.
when you're going through the process of applying or of learning this to just reorder the steps of
단계를 재정렬하기 위해 이것을 적용하거나 배우는 과정을 거칠 때
applying these regularizations in this fashion. When it comes time for your implementation,
이러한 정규화를 이러한 방식으로 적용합니다. 구현 시간이 되면
you can toy around a little bit with this. I prefer doing the implementation of the paper
이것으로 조금 놀 수 있습니다. 나는 논문을 구현하는 것을 선호합니다
proposes because we have that layer norm on the signal plus the residual instead of just the residual component.
우리는 단지 잔차 성분 대신에 잔차와 함께 신호에 대한 레이어 표준을 갖기 때문에 제안합니다.
Now, we have all of the pieces that are needed to build the encoder and the decoder. Let's talk
이제 인코더와 디코더를 구축하는 데 필요한 모든 부분이 준비되었습니다. 얘기하자
about the encoder first. The encoder itself, or an encoder layer, is a composable block
먼저 인코더에 대해. 인코더 자체 또는 인코더 레이어는 구성 가능한 블록입니다.
for the task of encoding an input sequence representation with this self-attention that
이 self-attention을 사용하여 입력 시퀀스 표현을 인코딩하는 작업에 대해
we've talked about. It's going to be taking in whatever the arbitrary input. Maybe it's the
우리는 이야기했습니다. 임의의 입력이 무엇이든 받아들일 것입니다. 어쩌면 그것은
original signal. Maybe it's one of the hidden states as we get deeper and deeper in this network,
원래 신호. 어쩌면 우리가 이 네트워크에 점점 더 깊이 들어가면서 숨겨진 상태 중 하나일 수도 있습니다.
and carrying out the self-attention to layer in that context, in the feedforward network,
피드포워드 네트워크에서 해당 맥락에서 레이어에 대한 셀프 어텐션을 수행합니다.
to exploit that context. The main idea of why we want to compose it in this repeatable block
해당 컨텍스트를 활용합니다. 이 반복 가능한 블록으로 구성하려는 이유에 대한 주요 아이디어
with fixed input and output dimensions is it makes it very easy to construct our model.
고정된 입력 및 출력 크기를 사용하면 모델을 구성하는 것이 매우 쉽습니다.
We can essentially stack these to get arbitrary depth, depending on how far we want to stack it,
우리는 기본적으로 이것을 쌓아서 얼마나 쌓고 싶은지에 따라 임의의 깊이를 얻을 수 있습니다.
and it allows the encoder to have this repeated multi-head attention, which gives us more parameters
그리고 이를 통해 인코더는 반복적인 다중 헤드 주의를 가질 수 있으며, 이는 우리에게 더 많은 매개변수를 제공합니다.
and the ability to model more complex positional interactions just by nature that we've gone a
그리고 우리가 경험한 본질적으로 더 복잡한 위치 상호 작용을 모델링하는 능력이 있습니다.
lot deeper. We've had more time to extract a relationship and then say, okay, this is contributing
훨씬 더 깊어요. 우리는 관계를 추출한 다음 '그래, 이것이 기여하고 있다'고 말할 시간이 더 많았습니다.
this much. The next time that we abstract a layer further, we can say, well, that was contributing
이만큼. 다음에 레이어를 더 추상화할 때, 그것이 기여했다고 말할 수 있습니다.
that much, and another element was contributing this much. Together, when those contribute that much,
그만큼, 또 다른 요소가 이만큼 기여하고 있었습니다. 함께 그 만큼 기여하면
this is what happens. We can build in more complex conditioning to the model just by going
이것이 일어나는 일입니다. 다음 단계를 수행하면 모델에 더 복잡한 조건을 적용할 수 있습니다.
deep. How we go about achieving this is implementing an encoder block with these
깊은. 이를 달성하는 방법은 다음을 사용하여 인코더 블록을 구현하는 것입니다.
sub-layer connections. We have the multi-head self-attention and then the feedforward with
하위 계층 연결. 우리는 다중 헤드 셀프 어텐션을 갖고 있고 다음으로 피드포워드를 사용합니다.
the sub-layer connections between each of them. As far as implementation goes, it's exactly what
그들 각각 사이의 하위 계층 연결. 구현에 관한 한, 그것은 정확히 무엇입니까?
I've described. The key is that we create our clones of the sub-layers so that we have multiple
설명했습니다. 핵심은 하위 레이어의 복제본을 생성하여 여러 레이어를 갖게 된다는 것입니다.
of them, and then we're just going to stack as many as we need. In this situation,
그런 다음 필요한 만큼 쌓아 올리겠습니다. 이러한 상황에서,
we flow into the feedforward or the multi-head self-attention first using this sub-layer connection,
먼저 이 하위 계층 연결을 사용하여 피드포워드 또는 다중 헤드 셀프 어텐션으로 이동합니다.
and then from the output of that sub-layer connection, we're going to flow into the feedforward,
그런 다음 해당 하위 계층 연결의 출력에서 ​​피드포워드로 흘러 들어가게 됩니다.
where it's modeling the residual, and then the rest of the sub-layer connection is going to
여기서는 잔차를 모델링하고 나머지 하위 계층 연결은
pull through that rest of that signal, and then we can stack these arbitrarily deep.
해당 신호의 나머지 부분을 처리한 다음 이를 임의의 깊이로 쌓을 수 있습니다.
The decoder, on the other hand, is going to be very similar to the encoder, but we need that
반면에 디코더는 인코더와 매우 유사하지만 다음이 필요합니다.
element of masking for the multi-head attention, so this causal masking that prevents you from
여러 머리 주의를 위한 마스킹 요소이므로 이 인과적 마스킹은
seeing the future, and we need an additional sub-layer that's going to be doing the exact
미래를 내다보려면 정확한 작업을 수행할 추가 하위 계층이 필요합니다.
same operation, except it's doing cross-attention. Where we're getting the signal from is going
Cross-Attention을 수행한다는 점을 제외하면 동일한 작업입니다. 우리가 신호를 받는 곳은 어디로 가는지
to come from the encoder for the keys and values rather than the decoded sequence thus far.
지금까지 디코딩된 시퀀스가 ​​아닌 키와 값에 대한 인코더에서 나옵니다.
As far as motivation for why we want to do the masking, I think I've explained this a little
마스킹을 하려는 동기에 대해서는 조금 설명드린 것 같습니다.
bit previously, but the main idea is it's preventing cheating, where the model is,
조금 전에도 그랬지만 주요 아이디어는 부정행위를 방지하는 것입니다. 모델은
I guess, forward-looking in the output when it's trying to learn how to predict the next token.
내 생각에는 다음 토큰을 예측하는 방법을 배우려고 할 때 출력을 미래 지향적으로 보는 것 같습니다.
So if you're going through the training task and it can see the future data, the model might fit
따라서 훈련 작업을 진행하고 미래 데이터를 볼 수 있다면 모델이 적합할 수 있습니다.
just to look at that next token. In fact, that's the best thing it could do to predict what the
다음 토큰을 보려고요. 사실, 그것이 무엇을 예측하기 위해 할 수 있는 최선의 방법입니까?
token should be, and it won't learn this causal relationship between previous tokens
토큰은 있어야 하며 이전 토큰 간의 인과 관계를 학습하지 않습니다.
and what should flow next. So we shield it from that information so that it can purely attend to
다음에는 무엇이 흘러야 할까요? 따라서 우리는 해당 정보로부터 보호하여 순전히 주의를 기울일 수 있습니다.
past context. As far as implementations go, we're going to have a very similar structure using
과거 맥락. 구현에 관한 한, 우리는 다음을 사용하여 매우 유사한 구조를 갖게 될 것입니다.
those sub-layer blocks that we talked about earlier, except what I've highlighted down below
아래에서 강조한 내용을 제외하고 이전에 이야기한 하위 레이어 블록
is with the self-attention that's masked, we go from x, x, x, so from one sequence
마스크된 self-attention을 사용하면 x, x, x에서 이동하므로 하나의 시퀀스에서
attending to itself with a mask that stops the future looking.
미래를 보지 못하게 하는 가면을 쓰고 자기 자신에게 주의를 기울이는 것입니다.
And then the next layer where we're doing this cross-attention, you'll notice that we have the
그리고 우리가 Cross-Attention을 수행하는 다음 레이어에는
queries coming from one source, but our keys and values are coming from this memory, which is
쿼리는 하나의 소스에서 나오지만 키와 값은 이 메모리에서 나옵니다.
the multi, it's coming from the attention to the encoder, so the encoded context that's gone
멀티는 인코더에 대한 관심에서 나오므로 인코딩된 컨텍스트는 사라집니다.
through and been developed. Finally, that'll pass through the feed-forward block to exploit
통해 개발되었습니다. 마지막으로 피드포워드 블록을 통과하여 이를 활용하게 됩니다.
that context again, and because we have this composable structure, we can stack them one on
해당 컨텍스트를 다시 한번 살펴보고 이 구성 가능한 구조를 갖고 있으므로 이를 하나씩 쌓을 수 있습니다.
top of each other to exploit and leverage all of that context that we've interwind into this
우리가 여기에 얽혀 있는 모든 맥락을 활용하고 활용하기 위해 서로 협력합니다.
polysemantic representation. So once we've established what the encoder blocks and decoder
다의미적 표현. 따라서 인코더와 디코더가 무엇을 차단하는지 설정한 후에는
blocks look like, before we can assemble the actual encoder-decoder structure itself,
실제 인코더-디코더 구조 자체를 조립하기 전에 블록은 다음과 같습니다.
we need to define the prediction head. As I described earlier, this is just the final
예측 헤드를 정의해야 합니다. 아까도 말씀드렸지만 이게 마지막이에요
thing that's going to take us to the output probabilities, and it's very simple. We do a
출력 확률을 알아보는 방법은 매우 간단합니다. 우리는
linear layer to convert into logits, and then we're going to throw through a softmax to produce
선형 레이어를 로지트로 변환한 다음 소프트맥스를 통해 생성합니다.
the probabilities for what the next token should be, and this is going to map us back to the
다음 토큰이 무엇이어야 하는지에 대한 확률을 알려주고 이는 우리를 다시 다음 토큰으로 매핑할 것입니다.
vocabulary capora that the actual tokens are from. So in an image space, these would be the
실제 토큰의 출처인 어휘 카포라입니다. 따라서 이미지 공간에서 이는 다음과 같습니다.
patches of an image. Where we're talking about a text space, these would be the tokens
이미지 패치. 우리가 텍스트 공간에 대해 이야기하고 있는 곳에서는 이것이 토큰이 될 것입니다.
that the sequence holds. Implementation is very straightforward. If you want, you can pause the
순서가 유지된다는 것입니다. 구현은 매우 간단합니다. 원한다면 일시중지할 수 있습니다.
presentation at this time and look at that. I'm just going to keep going to the actual assembly
지금 프레젠테이션을 보고 저것 좀 보세요. 난 그냥 실제 의회에 계속 갈거야
of the encoder-decoder structure, and I think this is where it's important to talk about
인코더-디코더 구조에 대해 이야기하는 것이 중요하다고 생각합니다.
what's going on and clear up a misconception. So I'll give you the picture here real quick.
무슨 일인지 오해를 풀겠습니다. 그래서 여기 사진을 아주 빨리 보여 드리겠습니다.
We essentially stack a whole bunch of the encoder blocks on top of each other and a
우리는 본질적으로 인코더 블록 전체를 서로 쌓고
whole bunch of the decoder blocks on top of each other. We then flow into that generator to produce
디코더 블록 전체가 서로 겹쳐져 있습니다. 그런 다음 해당 생성기로 흘러들어가
our most likely probabilities for what the next token should be, and then we know down the line
다음 토큰이 무엇이어야 하는지에 대한 가장 가능성 있는 확률, 그리고 우리는 라인을 알고 있습니다.
that's going to flow into that decoding process that's actually going to produce that token.
그것은 실제로 해당 토큰을 생성할 디코딩 프로세스로 흘러 들어갈 것입니다.
Implementation-wise, this is very simple. We're just going to use that clones. We're going to
구현 측면에서는 매우 간단합니다. 우리는 그 클론을 사용할 것입니다. 우리는
exploit that clones helper function that we made to create copies of the encoder and decoder blocks.
인코더 및 디코더 블록의 복사본을 생성하기 위해 만든 복제 도우미 기능을 활용합니다.
We're going to stack them on top of each other, and then when it comes time to predict,
우리는 그것들을 서로 쌓아올린 다음 예측할 때가 되면
you see in the forward pass, we just go through the number of blocks. They call the layers in
정방향 패스에서 볼 수 있듯이, 우리는 단지 블록 수를 통과합니다. 그들은 레이어를 호출합니다
their implementation here, but we're just going to do signal into the first encoder block, take
여기서는 구현을 하겠지만 첫 번째 인코더 블록에 신호를 보낼 것입니다.
that output, put it into the next decoder block, and so on. Or encoder goes into encoder, decoders
해당 출력을 다음 디코더 블록에 넣는 식으로 진행됩니다. 아니면 인코더가 인코더, 디코더로 들어갑니다.
flow into the decoders using that learn memory from the encoder as well.
인코더에서도 메모리를 학습하여 디코더로 유입됩니다.
And this brings us to that misconception about transformers, and this really, I believe,
이것이 우리에게 변압기에 대한 오해를 불러일으켰고, 제 생각에는 이것이 실제로
originated because of that figure that I keep showing with the times n,
n이라는 시간으로 계속해서 보여주고 있는 그 모습에서 비롯된 것인데,
and it's an incorrect understanding of what it means to stack layers.
레이어를 쌓는다는 것이 무엇을 의미하는지에 대한 잘못된 이해입니다.
So the notion of a whole transformer block being stacked on top of each other is incorrect,
따라서 전체 변압기 블록이 서로 쌓여 있다는 개념은 올바르지 않습니다.
and the main reason is that where an encoder flowing into the decoder for the cross-attention,
주된 이유는 크로스 어텐션을 위해 인코더가 디코더로 흘러 들어가는 경우,
one might think you just stack them on top of each other. You then don't get to exploit
누군가는 그것들을 서로 쌓아두기만 한다고 생각할 수도 있습니다. 그러면 악용할 수 없습니다.
in the earlier layers of the decoder, sorry, the rich context that's been accumulated throughout
디코더의 초기 레이어에서는 죄송합니다. 전체에 걸쳐 축적된 풍부한 컨텍스트
the encoder. So rather than having an encoder flow into the decoder and then the output of
인코더. 따라서 인코더가 디코더로 흘러 들어간 다음
that decoder flow into the next block or something like that, when we talk about stacking transformers,
디코더가 다음 블록으로 흐르거나 그와 비슷한 것, 스태킹 트랜스포머에 관해 이야기할 때,
we're talking about either stacking the encoders themselves to build a more rich representation
우리는 인코더 자체를 쌓아서 더욱 풍부한 표현을 구축하는 것에 대해 이야기하고 있습니다.
with the relational context embedded in the signal, or we're talking about stacking the
신호에 포함된 관계형 컨텍스트를 사용하거나
decoders to do the same thing, maybe do some cross-attention to grab information from somewhere
동일한 작업을 수행하는 디코더, 어딘가에서 정보를 가져오기 위해 교차 주의를 수행할 수도 있음
else, but the main idea is we want to be doing that self-attention and building a comprehensive
하지만 주요 아이디어는 우리가 자기 관심을 갖고 포괄적인 시스템을 구축하고 싶다는 것입니다.
representation through the signal, but with the purpose of producing a token in that case.
신호를 통해 표현하지만, 이 경우 토큰을 생성할 목적이 있습니다.
So when we talk about stacking transformers, it's stacking all of the encoders,
따라서 변압기 적층에 관해 이야기할 때는 모든 인코더를 적층하는 것입니다.
producing a single representation that has multiple bits of context about different
서로 다른 내용에 대한 여러 비트의 컨텍스트를 갖는 단일 표현을 생성합니다.
ways you could view the problem, so the decoder does have a rich representation it can query into.
문제를 볼 수 있는 방법이 있으므로 디코더는 쿼리할 수 있는 풍부한 표현을 갖게 됩니다.
And then after having each decoder stacked on top of each other with a flow,
그런 다음 각 디코더를 흐름으로 서로 쌓은 후,
but they all grab information during the cross-attention from the final output of the
하지만 그들은 모두 최종 출력에서 ​​교차주의를 기울이는 동안 정보를 얻습니다.
final encoder block. And this is exactly what we do when we assemble the encoder-decoder. We build
최종 인코더 블록. 이것이 바로 우리가 인코더-디코더를 조립할 때 하는 일입니다. 우리는 짓는다
our encoder by stacking the encoder blocks, the decoder by stacking the decoder blocks,
인코더는 인코더 블록을 쌓아서 만들고, 디코더는 디코더 블록을 쌓아서 만들고,
we throw a generator on top, and we put it all together to get this encoder-decoder,
우리는 생성기를 맨 위에 놓고 이를 모두 모아 이 인코더-디코더를 얻습니다.
where inputs will flow in through the encoder that we see inside of the encode process,
입력은 인코딩 프로세스 내부에서 볼 수 있는 인코더를 통해 유입됩니다.
and in the forward process we can see we're calling the encode on the source,
순방향 프로세스에서는 소스에서 인코딩을 호출하는 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
and then that output will flow into the decoder process as the memory, along with the previously
그런 다음 해당 출력은 이전 출력과 함께 메모리로서 디코더 프로세스로 흘러 들어갑니다.
decoded sequence. Putting that all together, we get this architecture that is highly paralyzable,
디코딩된 시퀀스. 이 모든 것을 종합하면 매우 마비되기 쉬운 아키텍처를 얻을 수 있습니다.
and then to move from one iteration to another, we just decode
그런 다음 한 반복에서 다른 반복으로 이동하려면 디코딩하면 됩니다.
auto-regressively by predicting the next token, and then appending that to the previously
다음 토큰을 예측한 다음 이를 이전 토큰에 추가하여 자동 회귀적으로
decoded list, and continuing in that process. Here's a final implementation for actually
목록을 디코딩하고 해당 프로세스를 계속 진행합니다. 실제로 최종 구현은 다음과 같습니다.
making this model. The most important part is at the very bottom here, where we make sure we go
이 모델을 만드는 중입니다. 가장 중요한 부분은 여기 맨 아래에 있습니다.
through the process of independently initializing all of the parameters in the model, since we've
모델의 모든 매개변수를 독립적으로 초기화하는 과정을 통해
used this clone helper function so pervasively. We want to make sure that we don't accidentally
이 복제 도우미 기능을 광범위하게 사용했습니다. 실수로 발생하지 않도록 하고 싶습니다.
have shared parameters that are trying to learn too many tasks or converging to one modality of
너무 많은 작업을 학습하려고 하거나 하나의 양식으로 수렴하려는 공유 매개변수가 있습니다.
prediction. With that, we've gone through the implementation of the transformer from the ground
예측. 이를 통해 우리는 지상에서 변압기를 구현하는 과정을 거쳤습니다.
up, kind of assembling out the architecture like a Lego house. I'm now going to talk briefly about
마치 레고 하우스처럼 건축물을 조립하는 것과 같습니다. 지금부터 간략하게 이야기하겠습니다.
training transformers. The notion of a model, I think, is incomplete if we just talk about
훈련 변압기. 내 생각에 모델의 개념은 우리가 단지 다음과 같이 이야기한다면 불완전하다고 생각합니다.
architecture, like with people where nature and nurture both play a role in how we express and
자연과 양육이 모두 우리가 표현하고 표현하는 방식에 중요한 역할을 하는 사람들과 마찬가지로 건축도 마찬가지입니다.
evolve in our world. Models are a product of both their architecture, so the structure that they
우리 세상에서 진화하세요. 모델은 두 아키텍처의 산물입니다.
have, and how they were trained. The training influences how the parameters in the model are
가지고 있는지, 어떻게 훈련받았는지. 훈련은 모델의 매개변수가 어떻게 결정되는지에 영향을 미칩니다.
expressed or what they have learned. This comes to the notion of garbage in, garbage out. If you go
표현한 것이나 배운 것. 이것은 쓰레기가 들어오고 쓰레기가 나온다는 개념에 이르게 됩니다. 당신이 가면
through a terrible training process, no matter how good your architecture is, your model is going
끔찍한 훈련 과정을 거치면 아키텍처가 아무리 훌륭하더라도 모델은 발전할 것입니다.
to underperform, because the model at the end of the day or the architecture is fitting to the training
결국 모델이나 아키텍처가 교육에 적합하기 때문에 성능이 저하됩니다.
data through this training process. If a transformer architecture, which we know has the ability to
이 훈련 과정을 통해 데이터를 수집합니다. 우리가 알고 있는 트랜스포머 아키텍처에 다음과 같은 기능이 있다면
attend bidirectionally through the self-attention to all elements in a sequence, if it is shown
표시된 경우 시퀀스의 모든 요소에 대한 self-attention을 통해 양방향으로 참석합니다.
examples that encourage bidirectional attention, it will learn that. Subsequent papers like BERT
양방향 주의를 장려하는 예를 통해 이를 학습하게 됩니다. BERT와 같은 후속 논문
use large-scale pre-training to learn and encourage that bidirectional expression of the
대규모 사전 훈련을 사용하여 양방향 표현을 학습하고 장려합니다.
transformer parameters. But on the alternative side, if it's shown examples that only require
변압기 매개변수. 그러나 대안적인 측면에서 단지 필요한 예가 표시된다면
rightward-looking attention, so that causal attention where you are looking at the past only,
과거만을 바라보는 인과적 관심이
it may express more unidirectional behavior, and it won't generalize as well.
보다 단방향적인 동작을 표현할 수 있으며 일반화되지도 않습니다.
So this is just a quick synopsis of the fact that when we have a transformer architecture, we want
따라서 이것은 변환기 아키텍처가 있을 때 우리가 원하는 사실을 간단히 요약한 것입니다.
to make sure we go through a good training procedure. But what Vaswani and his colleagues do in the
우리가 좋은 훈련 절차를 거치도록 하기 위해서입니다. 하지만 Vaswani와 그의 동료들은
paper is they train using mass attention. So they build out this attention mechanism that can
종이는 대중의 관심을 이용해 훈련한다는 것입니다. 그래서 그들은 다음과 같은 주의 메커니즘을 구축합니다.
prevent forward-looking bias, where they give a set of pre-tokens, and they want to predict
사전 토큰 세트를 제공하고 예측하려는 미래 예측 편견을 방지합니다.
an output target token based on only the previous inputs. And how they do this at a large scale is
이전 입력만을 기반으로 하는 출력 대상 토큰입니다. 그리고 그들이 이것을 대규모로 수행하는 방법은 다음과 같습니다.
they batch up all of the training jobs by just saying, this is what you can see in a previous
그들은 다음과 같이 말함으로써 모든 훈련 작업을 일괄 처리합니다. 이것은 이전 동영상에서 볼 수 있는 것입니다.
window, and this is the single token you're trying to predict. So that for a full sequence,
창이며 이것이 예측하려는 단일 토큰입니다. 전체 시퀀스의 경우
you don't need to run through iterating, generating the first one, then the second
반복을 통해 첫 번째 항목을 생성한 다음 두 번째 항목을 생성할 필요가 없습니다.
token, then the third token, etc. You can just give in some finite window of the past,
토큰, 세 번째 토큰 등입니다. 과거에 대한 유한한 창을 제공할 수 있습니다.
predict what the next token would be, and you can essentially build a sliding window over all the
다음 토큰이 무엇인지 예측하면 기본적으로 모든 토큰에 대해 슬라이딩 창을 구축할 수 있습니다.
data and train on all windows and all targets at the same time. So we've talked about this a
모든 창과 모든 대상에 대해 동시에 데이터를 수집하고 훈련합니다. 그래서 우리는 이것에 대해 이야기했습니다.
little bit, how it's actually implemented is creating a subsequent mask or this causal mask.
조금, 실제로 구현되는 방식은 후속 마스크 또는 이 인과 마스크를 만드는 것입니다.
This is done by just saying for a window, so let's say we are at token four, I can see tokens
이는 창에 대해 말하기만 하면 됩니다. 따라서 토큰 4에 있다고 가정하면 토큰을 볼 수 있습니다.
three, two, one, and zero, but none of the future. So that's what the figure off to the side shows.
3, 2, 1, 0이지만 미래는 없습니다. 이것이 바로 옆에 있는 그림이 보여주는 것입니다.
We can generate that mask, and because we've baked in the parameter of a mask to our attention
우리는 해당 마스크를 생성할 수 있으며, 주의를 끌기 위해 마스크의 매개변수를 구웠기 때문입니다.
function, it's actually really easy to implement this and use it. So we pass in the subsequent mask
함수를 구현하고 사용하는 것은 실제로 매우 쉽습니다. 따라서 다음 마스크를 전달합니다.
to our mass self-attention in the decoder block when we're training,
우리가 훈련할 때 디코더 블록에 있는 대량의 self-attention에 대해
and we make sure that it can only see the past. Now, when we're handing this in, how the authors
그리고 우리는 그것이 과거만 볼 수 있도록 합니다. 이제 우리가 이것을 제출할 때 저자들은 어떻게
apply this masking is they do it before the softmax, but because the softmax is going to be going
이 마스킹을 적용하면 소프트맥스 이전에 수행하지만 소프트맥스가 진행될 것이기 때문입니다.
and normalizing to present to convert this to a probability, we need to set the number as negatively
이것을 확률로 변환하기 위해 현재로 정규화하면 숫자를 음수로 설정해야 합니다.
as we can. So the authors do negative one to the power of negative nine, which is a very negative
우리가 할 수 있는 대로. 그래서 저자들은 음수 1의 음수 9승을 합니다. 이는 매우 음수입니다.
number. So when it goes through the softmax for these keys and queries, the keys and queries,
숫자. 따라서 이러한 키와 쿼리, 키와 쿼리에 대한 소프트맥스를 통과하면
when we're referring to the keys that the query shouldn't have the information from,
쿼리에서 정보를 가져서는 안 되는 키를 언급할 때
the values of them are going to be so negative that it becomes zero or it doesn't wait
그 값은 너무 음수가 되어 0이 되거나 기다리지 않게 됩니다.
into what that stage of the iteration looks like during this autoregressive generation.
이 자동 회귀 생성 동안 반복의 해당 단계가 어떻게 보이는지 살펴보겠습니다.
So that's the main idea here. Set it very negatively. We can then pass that in to our
이것이 바로 여기의 주요 아이디어입니다. 매우 부정적으로 설정하십시오. 그런 다음 이를 우리에게 전달할 수 있습니다.
softmax, and it's going to convert these into zeros or non-impacking terms, things that don't
소프트맥스는 이를 0 또는 임팩킹되지 않는 용어로 변환합니다.
have weight, so we're not paying attention to them because we couldn't be paying attention. Those
체중이 있어서 주의를 기울일 수 없기 때문에 주의를 기울이지 않고 있습니다. 저것들
tokens haven't been seen yet. With that said, I'm going to hand back over to Aveline. She's going
토큰은 아직 확인되지 않았습니다. 그렇게 말하면 나는 Aveline에게 다시 넘겨 줄 것입니다. 그녀는 간다
to tie up the presentation with a little bit of results and conversation on the impact along with
약간의 결과와 그 영향에 대한 대화로 프레젠테이션을 마무리합니다.
some early adoption of transformers for other domains.
다른 도메인에 대한 변환기의 초기 채택.
Yeah, so like James said, I will touch on the experimentations that the authors of the
네, James가 말했듯이, 저는
Attention to All You Need paper reported. They, similarly to the previous attention papers,
필요한 모든 것에 주의를 기울이십시오(Attention to All You Need) 보고서가 보고되었습니다. 그들은 이전 주의 논문과 유사하게,
their experimentations were based on text translation, so between English and German and
그들의 실험은 텍스트 번역을 기반으로 했기 때문에 영어와 독일어,
English and French. For their experimentations, they reported two different metrics. One was a
영어와 프랑스어. 실험을 위해 그들은 두 가지 다른 측정항목을 보고했습니다. 하나는
performance metric, and another one was the training cost required for training their models.
성능 지표이고 또 다른 하나는 모델 훈련에 필요한 훈련 비용이었습니다.
What we see here is for the transformer models, the big model performs quite well on the blue score.
여기서 볼 수 있는 것은 트랜스포머 모델에 대한 것이며, 큰 모델은 파란색 점수에서 꽤 좋은 성능을 발휘합니다.
It outperforms most of the other state-of-the-art models at the time. As for the training cost,
이는 당시의 다른 최신 모델 대부분을 능가합니다. 훈련비용의 경우,
what we notice here is that both the big and the base model have a lower training cost than the
여기서 우리가 알 수 있는 것은 큰 모델과 기본 모델 모두 훈련 비용이 더 낮다는 것입니다.
other state-of-the-art models. The big model had a training cost that was about 10 to the 19,
다른 최신 모델. 큰 모델의 훈련 비용은 약 10~19 정도였고,
whereas all the other ones were as small as 10 to the 20. This is a pretty
반면 다른 것들은 모두 10의 20만큼 작았습니다.
revolutionary thing where we see an increase in performance, but we see a decrease in training
성과는 향상되지만 훈련량은 감소하는 혁명적인 현상입니다.
cost. Now, this paper itself has been highly influential. Its citation count from this week
비용. 이제 이 논문 자체가 큰 영향력을 미쳤습니다. 이번 주 인용 횟수
at the end of March was 113,000 citations, and I'm sure that will change as time goes on,
3월 말에는 113,000회의 인용이 있었고 시간이 지나면서 그 수치도 바뀔 것이라고 확신합니다.
but the transformer architecture has been used as the basis for many state-of-the-art models.
그러나 트랜스포머 아키텍처는 많은 최첨단 모델의 기초로 사용되었습니다.
It is a fundamental backbone or building block for all LLMs that we know and use today, like GPT-4,
이는 GPT-4와 같이 오늘날 우리가 알고 사용하는 모든 LLM의 기본 백본 또는 빌딩 블록입니다.
Lama-2, Gemini. In that sense, it's been quite revolutionary for AI tools and technologies
라마-2, 쌍둥이자리. 그런 의미에서 AI 도구와 기술은 상당히 혁명적이었습니다.
that have really emerged since this paper was published back in 2017.
이 논문이 2017년에 출판된 이후 실제로 나타났습니다.
So, as for early adoption in other domains, in particular computer vision, we see the image
따라서 다른 영역, 특히 컴퓨터 비전의 조기 채택에 대해서는 다음과 같은 이미지를 볼 수 있습니다.
transformer emerge in 2018. Now, they didn't use the transformer architecture directly,
2018년에 Transformer가 등장했습니다. 이제 그들은 Transformer 아키텍처를 직접 사용하지 않았습니다.
but they were inspired by this architecture on text and wanted to apply it on images. So,
하지만 그들은 텍스트의 이러한 아키텍처에서 영감을 얻었고 이를 이미지에 적용하고 싶었습니다. 그래서,
the way that they used this idea was they positionally encode image pixels and then used a sort of
그들이 이 아이디어를 사용한 방식은 이미지 픽셀을 위치적으로 인코딩한 다음 일종의
local self-attention mechanism for different pixels in a query block to other pixels surrounding
쿼리 블록의 여러 픽셀과 주변의 다른 픽셀에 대한 로컬 자체 주의 메커니즘
that query block, making up a memory block. So, it considers pixels in a local neighborhood
해당 쿼리 블록이 메모리 블록을 구성합니다. 따라서 지역 인근의 픽셀을 고려합니다.
around the query position. Nowadays, this methodology or process isn't heavily used.
쿼리 위치 주변. 요즘에는 이 방법이나 프로세스가 많이 사용되지 않습니다.
What people have found is that global attention in images is more effective and it's just global
사람들이 발견한 것은 이미지에 대한 전 세계적인 관심이 더 효과적이며 전 세계적이라는 것입니다.
attention is needed to acquire the results and the performance that we're looking for with these
이를 통해 우리가 원하는 결과와 성과를 얻으려면 주의가 필요합니다.
types of tools and subsequent models that use this global attention have been found to be much more
이러한 세계적인 관심을 활용하는 도구 및 후속 모델의 유형은 훨씬 더 많은 것으로 밝혀졌습니다.
powerful. An example of this is the vision transformer, which does use the encode, the
강한. 이에 대한 예는 인코딩을 사용하는 비전 변환기입니다.
transformer architecture directly. In particular, they use the encoder for image classification.
트랜스포머 아키텍처를 직접적으로 구현합니다. 특히, 이미지 분류를 위해 인코더를 사용합니다.
This is the original paper from 2020, which called an images worth 16 by 16 words,
16 x 16 단어 상당의 이미지를 호출한 2020년 원본 논문입니다.
transformers for image recognition at scale. Now, this is a whole field of study,
대규모 이미지 인식을 위한 변환기. 자, 이것은 전체 연구 분야입니다.
but this was the original paper that I'm just going to briefly mention here.
하지만 이것이 제가 여기서 간단히 언급하려는 원본 논문이었습니다.
Like I said, they only use the vanilla transformer encoder, and what they do is they take an image,
제가 말했듯이 그들은 바닐라 트랜스포머 인코더만 사용하고 그들이 하는 일은 이미지를 찍는 것입니다.
they slice this into different patches to produce a sort of sequence, then they embed
그들은 이것을 일종의 시퀀스를 생성하기 위해 다른 패치로 분할한 다음 삽입합니다.
with positional encodings these patches into embedded and encoded sequences,
위치 인코딩을 사용하면 이러한 패치를 임베디드 및 인코딩된 시퀀스로 변환할 수 있습니다.
and then pass this into the transformer encoder, add on an MLP head for classification,
그런 다음 이를 변압기 인코더에 전달하고 분류를 위해 MLP 헤드를 추가합니다.
and build an image classifier that way. This was found to be very powerful,
그런 식으로 이미지 분류기를 구축하세요. 이는 매우 강력한 것으로 확인되었으며,
and like I said, lots have been built on top of this in recent years.
제가 말했듯이 최근 몇 년 동안 이를 기반으로 많은 것들이 만들어졌습니다.
All right, so that concludes our presentation. I hope you enjoyed
좋습니다, 이것으로 프레젠테이션을 마치겠습니다. 나는 당신이 즐겼기를 바랍니다
all of this information about self-attention and transformers that we have presented here.
여기에 제시된 self-attention 및 변환기에 대한 모든 정보입니다.
Feel free to leave any comments or questions if you'd like.
원하시면 언제든지 의견이나 질문을 남겨주세요.
Yeah, and the YouTube comments. We also have an additional sign just with a couple of discussion
네, 그리고 유튜브 댓글도요. 몇 가지 논의만으로 추가 표시도 있습니다.
questions that I'm just going to put up here. We're not going to discuss this at length in
제가 여기에 올리려는 질문이 있습니다. 우리는 이 문제에 대해 길게 논의하지 않을 것입니다.
our presentation or at all, really, but just feel free to pause the video at this point and think
하지만 이 시점에서는 영상을 잠시 멈추고 생각해 보세요.
about your understanding or how you've come to learn more about the transformer through our
당신의 이해 또는 우리를 통해 변압기에 대해 더 많이 알게 된 방법에 대해
presentation. Additionally, if you have further questions, feel free to leave them in the comment
프레젠테이션. 추가적으로 더 궁금하신 점은 댓글로 남겨주세요
section of this video, and if we have some time, I'd love to kind of start a discourse up there.
시간이 있으면 위에서부터 토론을 시작하고 싶습니다.